<driver id="driver/alc2000">
 <name>alc2000</name>
 <url>http://www.epkowa.co.jp/english/linux_e/lpd_e.html</url>
 <execution>
  <ghostscript />
  <prototype>gs -q -dBATCH -dSAFER -dNOPAUSE -sDEVICE=alc2000%A%Z -sOutputFile=- -</prototype>
 </execution>
 <comments>
  <en>

    The Epson color laser printers understand PCL 5e or PCL 6 but
    print only in grayscale with these languages. PostScript is an
    option which costs around 250 US$. This driver provided by Epson
    allows colour printing on the non-PostScript models and gives some
    additional options to the supported printers.&lt;p&gt;

    Version 1.0.4 of this driver works only with GhostScript 5.50, not
    with GhostScript 6.5x and newer.  For the new GhostScript versions
    use &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.linuxprinting.org/download/printing/ghostscript-6.51-Epson_eplaseren.patch&quot;&gt;this
    patch&lt;/a&gt; from Crutcher Dunnavant (Red Hat).&lt;p&gt;

    The driver&apos;s web page offers the new version 3.0.2 only for
    the AcuLaser C4000, but in reality it supports all printers which
    the previous version already supported plus the AcuLaser C4000. So
    choose always the AcuLaser C4000 as your printer model when
    downloading the driver, regardless what model you really
    have. During the installation take care again which model you
    have. This driver version is prepared for both GhostScript 5.x and
    6.x. For GhostScript 7.x or newer a small fix is needed: Execute
    the following command line in the main directory of the unpacked
    driver source package:&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;perl -p -i -e
    &quot;s/GS_VERSION_MAJOR\s*==\s*6/GS_VERSION_MAJOR &amp;gt;=
    6/&quot; gdevescv.c gdevesmv.c&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    Then the driver also compiles with these versions of
    GhostScript.&lt;p&gt;

    On the home page of this driver is told that it only supports
    grayscale but I have tested it and it prints in
    colour. Unfortunately, the driver needs a lot of resources and so
    for high-resolution photos 512 MB RAM and a fast processor are
    recommended (or alternatively the PostScript module).&lt;p&gt;

  </en>
 </comments>
 <printers>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Epson-AcuLaser_C2000</id>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Epson-AcuLaser_C2000PS</id>
  </printer>
 </printers>
</driver>
