<driver id="driver/drv_x125">
 <name>drv_x125</name>
 <url>http://sourceforge.net/projects/x125-linux/</url>
 <execution>
  <filter />
  <prototype>%Dx125_cmyk_print.sh $size %C %A %B %E</prototype>
 </execution>
 <comments>
  <en>

    Version 0.2.3.  REQUIRES SPECIAL SETUP (see below).&lt;p&gt;
    
    Simple driver for the Lexmark X125 printer.  Supports 300x600,
    600x600 or 1200x600 dpi in grayscale (using only the black ink
    cartridge), CMY (using only the color cartridge) or CMYK (using
    both black and color).  Also supports bidirectional printing
    (fast!).  Note that black mode is significantly less CPU intensive
    than color modes.  A resolution of 2400 dpi is not yet supported.
    The driver is still in experimental state but works.  Bug reports
    and feature requests are welcome and should be made to the
    sourceforge project.&lt;p&gt;
    
    Because the driver needs to read status codes from the printer,
    this driver requires special setup which will be shown here for
    Red Hat systems, on other distributions it should work in a
    similar way. For Queue type, select Locally-connected, click
    "Custom Device" and specify /dev/null as the device.  If you don't
    specify /dev/null, nothing will happen when you print because the
    driver won't be able to connect directly to the printer since the
    resource will be in use.  If your printer has locked up in the
    past, you may need to unplug it from the power outlet and plug it
    back in before this driver will work.  If your printer is not
    connected to /dev/usb/lp0, you can specify a different device
    using the driver options.&lt;p&gt;
    
    Note that this driver must always run on the machine to which the
    printer is directly connected. You cannot hook your printer onto
    an ethernet print box. If you wish to be able to set up your Linux
    box as a Samba printing host and let the Windows clients use the
    Windows driver from Lexmark, use the x125_network driver on your
    Samba server. It is also available on the sourceforge
    site.&lt;p&gt;

  </en>
 </comments>
 <printers>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Lexmark-X125</id><!-- Lexmark X125 -->
  </printer>
 </printers>
</driver>
