<driver id="driver/lx5000">
  <name>lx5000</name>
  <url>http://pbw.id.au/lexmark/lexmark.html</url>
  <obsolete replace="pbm2l7k" />
  <thirdpartysupplied />
  <execution>
    <ghostscript />
    <prototype>gs -q -dBATCH -dPARANOIDSAFER -dQUIET -dNOPAUSE -dNOMEDIAATTRS -dNOINTERPOLATE -sDEVICE=lx5000 %A%Z -sOutputFile=- -</prototype>
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en> 

    This is a beta version of a driver for the Lexmark 5000. It
    supports unidirectional colour printing at 1200x600, 600x600, and
    300x600 dpi. One can switch between colour and b/w, adjust the
    cartridges, and choose the page drying time.&lt;p&gt;

    The driver is known to work with the Lexmark 5000 and the
    Z51.&lt;p&gt;

    The driver was part of the Ghostscript upstream source code for a
    long time but recently it was removed from the source code repository
    for version 9.05 as it does not work reliably
    any more with current Ghostscript (version 9.04). It causes
    Ghostscript to hang in an infinite loop on several files, requiring the
    user to cancel the job. See the &lt;a
    href="http://bugs.ghostscript.com/show_bug.cgi?id=691820"&gt;Ghostscript
    bug report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

    There was no time invested anymore to actually fix the problem as
    the supported printers are very old, so there will be only very
    few users and they would rather buy a new, more modern printer
    instead of making their old Lexmarks work again.&lt;p&gt;

    For everyone who still want to work with the printer and experiment with
    this driver or even fix it, the original
    home page of the driver is still available and the latest code of the
    driver and a copy of the printer's protocol; information is available
    &lt;a
    href="/download/printing/lx5000/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

    Use the "&lt;a href="/driver/pbm2l7k"&gt;pbm2l7k&lt;/a&gt;" driver
    if you want to quickly get these printers to work.&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
  <printers>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-5000</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z51</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z82</id>
    </printer>
  </printers>
</driver>
