<driver id="driver/lxm3200-tweaked">
  <name>lxm3200-tweaked</name>
  <url>http://www.openprinting.org/download/printing/</url>
  <thirdpartysupplied />
  <execution>
    <ghostscript />
    <prototype>gs -q -dBATCH -dPARANOIDSAFER -dQUIET -dNOPAUSE -sDEVICE=lxm3200%A%Z -sOutputFile=- -</prototype>
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>

    Tweaked version of Daniel Gordini's &quot;lxm3200&quot; driver for
    the Lexmark 3200. Boer Attila (boera at unitbv dot ro) and Tomas
    Groth (tomasgroth at hotmail dot com) discovered that this driver
    works also on the Z12 and the Z31 when one does some small
    tweaking on it. So they have made a modified version of the
    original driver, with an additional
    &quot;&lt;tt&gt;-dmodel=&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&quot;
    (Lexmark 3200: &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;tt&gt; = 0&lt;/tt&gt;, Z12:
    &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;tt&gt; = 1&lt;/tt&gt;, Z31:
    &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;tt&gt; = 2&lt;/tt&gt;) option to fit the
    driver to the appropriate model.&lt;p&gt;

    Notes:&lt;p&gt;

    The 1200 dpi will come out somewhat dark, correct this by the
    gamma correction of CUPS, or use the 600dpi resolution (native
    resolution of the printer).&lt;p&gt;

    Unidirectional printing on the Z12 and the Z31 is possible and gives a
    much higher printout quality.&lt;p&gt;

    From the Z31 there came out models which need different margin
    settings. If the print head of your Z31 goes over the end of its
    rails and makes strange noise, use the
    &quot;&lt;tt&gt;-dz31m=&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&quot;
    option where &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; is an integer number adjusting
    the margins. Default (when not using the option) is 100, You
    should try something like 300, but other values can also
    apply.&lt;p&gt;

    The Compaq IJ750 is a rebadged Lexmark 3200, so use it with
    &quot;&lt;tt&gt;-dmodel=0&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;.&lt;p&gt;

    The Z22 and Z32 have protocols similar to the Lexmark 3200 and
    work partially with this driver
    (&quot;&lt;tt&gt;-dmodel=0&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;). Note that you have
    to turn off and on the Z22/Z32 after the job has finished. For
    black text printing this driver is usable on the Z22/Z32. But note
    that these printers are not officially supported by this
    driver. Use Lexmark's drivers for the Z22/Z32.&lt;p&gt;

    This driver is also in the CVS of &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.cups.org/ghostscript.php&quot;&gt;ESP
    Ghostscript&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;lxm3200&quot; device). When one does
    not use the
    &quot;&lt;tt&gt;-dmodel=&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&quot;
    option, the driver behaves as the original &quot;lxm3200&quot;
    driver.&lt;p&gt;

    Alternative download place (probably not the newest version):
    &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.distantvoices.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.distantvoices.org/&lt;/a&gt;

  </en>
  </comments>
  <printers>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Compaq-IJ750</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-3200</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z12</id>
      <comments>
        <en>
    To avoid that the printer makes strange noise, print only in
    bidirectional mode (&quot;-dbidir=1&quot;). This printer is only
    tested with the black cartridge.
    </en>
      </comments>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z22</id>
      <comments>
        <en>
    You have to turn off and on the printer after the job has
    finished. For black text printing this driver is usable on the
    Z22/Z32.
    </en>
      </comments>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z31</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z32</id>
      <comments>
        <en>
    You have to turn off and on the printer after the job has
    finished. For black text printing this driver is usable on the
    Z22/Z32.
    </en>
      </comments>
    </printer>
  </printers>
</driver>
