<driver id="driver/lxm3200">
  <name>lxm3200</name>
  <url>http://lxm3200.sourceforge.net/</url>
  <obsolete replace="lxm3200-tweaked" />
  <thirdpartysupplied />
  <execution>
    <ghostscript />
    <prototype>gs -q -dBATCH -dPARANOIDSAFER -dQUIET -dNOPAUSE -dNOINTERPOLATE -sDEVICE=lxm3200%A%Z -sOutputFile=- -</prototype>
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>
    &lt;b&gt;New Maintainer Wanted!&lt;/b&gt; Daniel Gordini, the
    current maintainer of this driver, cannot maintain it any more for
    personal reasons. After not being able to do anything on it in the
    last nine months he told me that the best is that someone else
    overtakes the project. He also cannot maintain the driver inside
    Gimp-Print any more and due to the fast development of Gimp-Print
    this driver stopped working.&lt;p&gt;

    So I ask all people with a Lexmark 3200 and programming skills for
    thinking about overtaking this project, especially as Gimp-Print
    driver. Because the protocols of the Z22, Z31, and Z32 are similar
    you do not work on a dead driver, expand it to work correctly also
    on these models (it already works partially). The Z52 (completely
    different protocol) advanced from &quot;Paperweight&quot; to
    &quot;Perfectly&quot; by a Gimp-Print driver having been written
    for it.&lt;p&gt;

    Please contact Daniel Gordini (dgordin at tin dot it) and the
    Gimp-Print team (gimp-print-devel at sourceforge dot net) if you
    want to volunteer.&lt;p&gt;

    If you want to print on a Lexmark 3200 &lt;b&gt;do not&lt;/b&gt;
    use Gimp-Print, the driver inside there does not work.&lt;p&gt;

    This is version 0.4.1 of Daniel Gordini's driver for the Lexmark
    3200. It replaces the old version 0.3 (driver entries &lt;a
    href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=lxm3200m&quot;&gt;lxm3200m&lt;/a&gt;,
    &lt;a
    href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=lxm3200c&quot;&gt;lxm3200c&lt;/a&gt;, and
    &lt;a
    href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=lxm3200p&quot;&gt;lxm3200p&lt;/a&gt;). It
    is nearly completely rewritten and supports now all resolutions
    (up to the 1200 dpi which the printer is able to do by its
    hardware), all colour modes (as before), bidirectional printing,
    multipass printing, and head alignment.&lt;p&gt;

    This is now the first stable release of the driver, the versions
    0.3 and 0.4 are not supported any more by the author.&lt;p&gt;

    Notes:&lt;p&gt;

    The 1200 dpi will come out somewhat dark, correct this by the
    gamma correction of CUPS, or use the 600dpi resolution (native
    resolution of the printer).&lt;p&gt;

    The Z22, Z31, Z32 have protocols similar to the Lexmark 3200 and
    work partially with this driver. Note that you have to turn off
    and on the Z22/Z32 after the job has finished. For black text
    printing this driver is usable on the Z22/Z32. But note that these
    printers are not officially supported by this driver. Use
    Lexmark's drivers for the Z22/Z32.&lt;p&gt;

    On the Z31 printouts will be not well centered. Use the
    &quot;lxm3200-tweaked&quot; driver for this printer.&lt;p&gt;

  </en>
  </comments>
  <printers>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Compaq-IJ750</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-3200</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z22</id>
      <comments>
        <en>

	  You have to turn off and on the printer after the job has
	  finished. For black text printing this driver is usable on the
	  Z22/Z32.

	</en>
      </comments>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z31</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Lexmark-Z32</id>
      <comments>
        <en>

	  You have to turn off and on the printer after the job has
	  finished. For black text printing this driver is usable on the
	  Z22/Z32.

	</en>
      </comments>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Xerox-WorkCentre_XK35c</id>
    </printer>
  </printers>
</driver>
