<driver id="driver/min12xxw">
  <name>min12xxw</name>
  <url>http://www.hinterbergen.de/mala/min12xxw/</url>
  <thirdpartysupplied />
  <packages>
    <package scope="general">*min12xxw*</package>
  </packages>
  <execution>
    <filter />
    <prototype>gs -q -dNOPAUSE -dPARANOIDSAFER -dBATCH -sDEVICE=pbmraw%A%Z -sOutputFile=- - | min12xxw%B</prototype>
    <margins>
      <general>
        <unit>in</unit>
        <relative />
        <top>0.17</top>
        <left>0.17</left>
        <right>0.17</right>
        <bottom>0.17</bottom>
      </general>
    </margins>
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>

       Min12xxw is a pbm filter by Manuel Tobias Schiller for various
       Minolta PagePro W-series (win)printers.  The driver basically
       works, but is new and reports are few; thus it should be
       considered experimental, and the purchase of a printer that
       relies upon this driver is not advisable.

       &lt;p&gt;

       Min12xxw should run on most *nix-like workstations without
       major problems. The only problem that is to be expected on
       non-Linux systems are missing library functions such as getline
       or getopt_long. The query options may or may not work on other
       systems, depending on the characteristics of the printer driver
       and the interface used (USB, very old style parallel port or a
       more recent one...).

       &lt;p&gt;

       Min12xxw was written without any documentation from the
       manufacturer. The description of the printer language may be
       inaccurate or even wrong because it was obtained by looking at
       the output of the Windows driver only. The code dealing with
       the compression of raster data is in its spirit heavily based
       on an initial driver by Adam Bocim.

       &lt;p&gt;

       This driver features querying the printer status and page
       counter, a suggestion made by Bruno Schoedlbauer, who also
       pointed me to a nice &lt;a
       href=&quot;http://benoit.papillault.free.fr/usbsnoop&quot;
       &gt;USB sniffer&lt;/a&gt; for Windows 98 and up by
       Benoit Papillault.

       &lt;p&gt;

       Even though this program has been designed with care and much
       thought, no one can guarantee that this program will not damage
       your printer, computer or even your neighbour's car, because it
       was built without knowing exactly how things work, it's only a
       (hopefully) reasonable guess. (However, my printer does still
       work, even after the testing phase when a lot of wrong stuff
       was sent to it. And my neighbour hasn't complained either...)

       &lt;p&gt;

       Most of the available paper sizes have not actually been
       verified to work as adverised - reports about successes or
       problems are welcome.  Also the code for querying the printer
       is not heavily tested. If you have comments to make or know
       more about the format than I do, please share your thoughts and
       your knowledge.

       &lt;p&gt;
   
    </en>
  </comments>
  <printers>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Minolta-PagePro_1200W</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Minolta-PagePro_1250W</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Minolta-PagePro_1300W</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Minolta-PagePro_1350W</id>
    </printer>
    <printer>
      <id>printer/Minolta-PagePro_1400W</id>
    </printer>
  </printers>
</driver>
