<driver id="driver/oki4drv">
 <name>oki4drv</name>
 <url>http://www.linuxprinting.org/download/printing/</url>
 <obsolete replace="oki4w" />
 <execution>
  <filter />
  <prototype>(echo -n "%F%A"; cat) 1&gt;/dev/oki4drv 2&gt;/dev/null</prototype>
 </execution>
 <comments>
  <en>
    Version 2.0 of this driver was developed in mid-2000 by Marcin
    Dalecki, with cooperation from Okidata, who sent him a printer and
    some protocol help.  (Heck, they sent me (Grant) one, too!)  &lt;p&gt;

    The driver comes with all sorts of performance warnings and is
    structured such that, if used according to the directions, it is
    slightly awkward to fit into normal print spoolers.  This weakness
    aside, it does work. The only flaw was that version 2.0 ejected a
    blank page after every job. This is fixed in version 2.1.&lt;p&gt;

    I (Grant) have constructed a framework that lets you use this
    driver under normal spoolers. The execution data and Foomatic
    support here assumes that you are using this framework. To use it,
    obtain oki4linux-2.1gst.tar.gz from the &lt;a
    href="download/printing/"&gt;download area&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

    Note that when you use these foomatic config files the printer
    must be always on the first parallel port. Any output device set
    in the spooler will be ignored. So the best is to choose
    &lt;tt&gt;/dev/null&lt;/tt&gt; as the destination device to not
    block the real device. In CUPS you do this with the URI
    &quot;&lt;tt&gt;file:/dev/null&lt;/tt&gt;&quot; and in LPD and
    LPRng with the entry &quot;&lt;tt&gt;lp=/dev/null&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;
    in the &lt;tt&gt;/etc/printcap&lt;/tt&gt; file.&lt;p&gt;

    Fl&amp;aacute;vio Coelho (fccoelho at uerj dot br) reports that the
    Okipage 6w only works with the old 2.0 version of the driver.
  </en>
 </comments>
 <printers>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Okidata-OL400w</id><!-- Okidata OL 400w -->
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Okidata-Okipage_4w</id><!-- Okidata Okipage 4w -->
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Okidata-Okipage_4wplus</id><!-- Okidata Okipage 4w+ -->
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Okidata-Okipage_6w</id><!-- Okidata Okipage 6w -->
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Okidata-Okipage_8w</id><!-- Okidata Okipage 8w -->
   <comments>
    <en>This printer works mostly with with oki4drv by Martin Dalecki.</en>
   </comments>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Okidata-Okipage_8w_Lite</id><!-- Okidata Okipage 8w Lite -->
   <comments>
    <en>This printer works mostly with with oki4drv by Martin Dalecki.</en>
   </comments>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/Okidata-Okipage_8z</id><!-- Okidata Okipage 8z -->
   <comments>
    <en>Requires version 2 of oki4linux?</en>
   </comments>
  </printer>
 </printers>
</driver>
