<driver id='driver/Postscript-NRG'>
  <name>Postscript-NRG</name>
  <url>http://www.nrg-group.com/</url>
  <supplier>Ricoh</supplier>
  <manufacturersupplied>NRG</manufacturersupplied>
  <!--not "thirdpartysupplied"-->
  <license>MIT</license>
  <licensetext>
    <en>

      MIT Open Source License

      See http://www.opensource.org/

      Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
      a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the
      "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including
      without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish,
      distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to
      permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to
      the following conditions:

      The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be
      included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

      THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
      EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
      MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
      NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE
      LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION
      OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION
      WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

    </en>
  </licensetext>
  <freesoftware />
  <!--not "nonfreesoftware"-->
  <nopatents />
  <!--not "patents"-->
  <supportcontacts>
    <supportcontact level="voluntary" url="http://forums.linux-foundation.org/list.php?30">Ricoh and OEM forum at OpenPrinting</supportcontact>
    <!--not level="commercial"-->
  </supportcontacts>
  <shortdescription>
    <en>
      PPD files for NRG's PostScript printers, supplied by Ricoh
    </en>
  </shortdescription>
  <functionality>
    <maxresx></maxresx>
    <maxresy></maxresy>
    <color />
    <!--not "monochrome"-->
    <text>100</text>
    <lineart>100</lineart>
    <graphics>100</graphics>
    <photo>100</photo>
    <load></load>
    <speed></speed>
  </functionality>
  <execution>
    <postscript/>
    <prototype></prototype>
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>

      Under this entry Ricoh's PPD files for their NRG-branded
      PostScript printers are hosted. PostScript printers are
      supported natively in Linux and Unix environments, so you only
      need the PPD file for your printer, no driver executables, to
      get access to all printing functionality. The PPD contains all
      information about properties and user-settable options which are
      specific to the printer and makes printing dialogs show these
      options and allow the user to control all the printer's
      functionality.&lt;p&gt;

      These PPDs are especially made for use on Linux/Unix
      systems. Especially they support all advanced printer features
      like Locked Print, Ducument Server, User Code, ... Note that
      although the printers are PostScript printers these PPD files
      need foomatic-rip. See the &lt;a
      href="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/en/OpenPrinting/Database/RicohFAQ"&gt;Ricoh
      FAQs&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;p&gt;

      Note that these printers work, like all other PostScript
      printers, with &lt;a
      href="show_driver.cgi?driver=Postscript"&gt;generic PostScript
      PPD files&lt;/a&gt;, but then you will not get access to all the
      printer-specific functionality.&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
  <printers>
  </printers>
</driver>
