<driver id="driver/Postscript2-Oce">
  <name>Postscript2-Oce</name>
  <url>http://www.oce.com/</url>
  <supplier>Oce</supplier>
  <manufacturersupplied>Oce|Imagistics</manufacturersupplied>
  <license>MIT</license>
  <licensetext>
    <en>

      MIT Open Source License

      See http://www.opensource.org/

      Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
      a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the
      &quot;Software&quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including
      without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish,
      distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to
      permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to
      the following conditions:

      The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be
      included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

      THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
      EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
      MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
      NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE
      LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION
      OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION
      WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

    </en>
  </licensetext>
  <shortdescription>
    <en>
      Manufacturer-supplied PPD files for Oce's PostScript level 2 printers
    </en>
  </shortdescription>
  <packages>
    <package scope="general" fingerprint="https://www.openprinting.org/download/printdriver/keys/openprinting">openprinting-ppds-postscript2-oce</package>
  </packages>
  <functionality>
    <color />
    <text>100</text>
    <lineart>100</lineart>
    <graphics>100</graphics>
    <photo>100</photo>
  </functionality>
  <execution>
    <postscript />
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>
      &lt;B&gt;All PPD files of this driver entry are available in the &lt;A href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenPrinting/ps-printer-app&quot;&gt;PostScript Printer Application&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/B&gt;&lt;P&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://snapcraft.io/ps-printer-app/embedded?button=black&amp;summary=true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid #CCC; border-radius: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

      Under this entry Oce's PPD files for their PostScript level 2
      printers are hosted. PostScript printers are supported natively
      in Linux and Unix environments, so you only need the PPD file
      for your printer, no driver executables, to get access to all
      printing functionality. The PPD contains all information about
      properties and user-settable options which are specific to the
      printer and makes printing dialogs show these options and allow
      the user to control all the printer's functionality.&lt;p&gt;

      The PPDs only support the printing functionality of the
      printers. To use extra functionality, like scanning, faxing, ... you
      will perhaps need additional software.&lt;p&gt;

      Note that these printers work, like all other PostScript
      printers, with &lt;a
      href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=Postscript&quot;&gt;generic PostScript
      PPD files&lt;/a&gt;, but then you will not get access to all the
      printer specific functionality.&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</driver>
