<driver id='driver/Postscript-HP'>
  <name>Postscript-HP</name>
  <url>http://hplipopensource.com/</url>
  <supplier>HP</supplier>
  <manufacturersupplied>HP|Apollo</manufacturersupplied>
  <!--not "thirdpartysupplied"-->
  <license>MIT</license>
  <licensetext>
    <en>

      MIT Open Source License

      See http://www.opensource.org/

      Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
      a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the
      "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including
      without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish,
      distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to
      permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to
      the following conditions:

      The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be
      included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

      THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
      EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
      MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
      NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE
      LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION
      OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION
      WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

    </en>
  </licensetext>
  <!--not "nonfreesoftware"-->
  <!--not "patents"-->
  <supportcontacts>
    <supportcontact level="voluntary" url="https://launchpad.net/hplip">HPLIP support and bug tracking system</supportcontact>
    <!--not level="commercial"-->
  </supportcontacts>
  <shortdescription>
    <en>
      PPD files for HP's PostScript printers which are not supported by HPLIP, supplied by HP
    </en>
  </shortdescription>
  <packages>
   <package scope="general">openprinting-ppds-postscript-hp</package>
  </packages>
  <functionality>
    <maxresx></maxresx>
    <maxresy></maxresy>
    <color />
    <!--not "monochrome"-->
    <text>100</text>
    <lineart>100</lineart>
    <graphics>100</graphics>
    <photo>100</photo>
    <load></load>
    <speed></speed>
  </functionality>
  <execution>
    <postscript/>
    <prototype></prototype>
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>

      Under this entry HP's PPD files for those PostScript printers
      are hosted which are not supported by HPLIP. These are most
      DesignJets (large format printers) and one PostScript standard
      format inkjet (OfficeJet 9100, HPLIP supports it only in PCL
      mode).&lt;p&gt;

      See the "&lt;a
      href="show_driver.cgi?driver=hplip"&gt;hplip&lt;/a&gt;" driver
      entry for all HP PostScript printers not mentioned
      here.&lt;p&gt;

      PostScript printers are supported natively in Linux and Unix
      environments, so you only need the PPD file for your printer, no
      driver executables, to get access to all printing
      functionality. The PPD contains all information about properties
      and user-settable options which are specific to the printer and
      makes printing dialogs show these options and allow the user to
      control all the printer's functionality.&lt;p&gt;

      Note that the PPDs are originally developed for the Mac OS X
      operating system. So they contain entries which are not made use
      of under Linux.&lt;p&gt;

      The PPDs only support the printing functionality of the
      printers. To use additional functionality, like ink/toner level
      check, inkjet head cleaning, scanning, faxing, ... you need
      &lt;a href="http://hplipopensource.com/"&gt;HPLIP&lt;/a&gt; in
      addition to the PPD files.&lt;p&gt;

      Note that these printers work, like all other PostScript
      printers, with &lt;a
      href="show_driver.cgi?driver=Postscript"&gt;generic PostScript
      PPD files&lt;/a&gt;, but then you will not get access to all the
      printer specific functionality.&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
  <printers>
  </printers>
</driver>
