<driver id='driver/Postscript-Lexmark'>
  <name>Postscript-Lexmark</name>
  <url>http://www.lexmark.com/</url>
  <supplier>Lexmark</supplier>
  <manufacturersupplied>Lexmark</manufacturersupplied>
  <!--not "thirdpartysupplied"-->
  <license>Redistribution with and without modification, keep copyright notice</license>
  <licensetext>
    <en>

******************************************************************************
              Copyright 2008 Lexmark International, Inc. All rights reserved.

******************************************************************************
**    License
******************************************************************************

Redistribution of this file, with or without modification, is permitted 
provided that the following conditions are met:
 
      Redistributions of this file must reproduce the above copyright notice, 
      this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the file and 
      documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

      Neither the name of Lexmark International, Inc. nor the names of its 
      contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived 
      from this file without specific prior written permission.

THIS FILE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" AND 
ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED 
WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE 
DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE 
FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL 
DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR 
SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER 
CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, 
OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE 
OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.

    </en>
  </licensetext>
  <!--not "patents"-->
  <!--no "supportcontacts"-->
  <shortdescription>
    <en>
      Manufacturer-supplied PPD files for Lexmark's PostScript printers
    </en>
  </shortdescription>
  <packages>
   <package scope="general">openprinting-ppds-postscript-lexmark</package>
  </packages>
  <functionality>
    <!--maxresx unknown-->
    <!--maxresy unknown-->
    <color />
    <!--not "monochrome"-->
    <text>100</text>
    <lineart>100</lineart>
    <graphics>100</graphics>
    <photo>100</photo>
    <!--load rating unknown-->
    <!--speed rating unknown-->
  </functionality>
  <execution>
    <postscript/>
    <prototype></prototype>
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>

      Under this entry Lexmark's PPD files for their PostScript printers
      are hosted. PostScript printers are supported natively in Linux
      and Unix environments, so you only need the PPD file for your
      printer, no driver executables, to get access to all printing
      functionality. The PPD contains all information about properties
      and user-settable options which are specific to the printer and
      makes printing dialogs show these options and allow the user to
      control all the printer's functionality.&lt;p&gt;

      The PPDs only support the printing functionality of the
      printers. To use extra functionality, like scanning and faxing
      you will need additional drivers.&lt;p&gt;

      Note that these printers work, like all other PostScript
      printers, with &lt;a
      href="show_driver.cgi?driver=Postscript"&gt;generic PostScript
      PPD files&lt;/a&gt;, but then you will not get access to all the
      printer specific functionality.&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
  <printers>
  </printers>
</driver>
