<driver id="driver/Postscript-Epson">
  <name>Postscript-Epson</name>
  <url>http://www.epson.com/</url>
  <supplier>Epson</supplier>
  <manufacturersupplied>Epson</manufacturersupplied>
  <license>MIT</license>
  <licensetext>
    <en>

      MIT Open Source License

      See http://www.opensource.org/

      Permission is hereby granted for redistribution of this file, provided
      that copyright notice is intact and the contents of this license
      agreement are not altered in any way from it original form.

      Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
      a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the
      &quot;Software&quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including
      without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish,
      distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to
      permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to
      the following conditions:

      The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be
      included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

      THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
      EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
      MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
      NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE
      LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION
      OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION
      WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

    </en>
  </licensetext>
  <shortdescription>
    <en>
      Manufacturer-supplied PPD files for Epson's PostScript printers
    </en>
  </shortdescription>
  <packages>
    <package scope="general">openprinting-ppds-postscript-epson</package>
  </packages>
  <functionality>
    <color />
    <text>100</text>
    <lineart>100</lineart>
    <graphics>100</graphics>
    <photo>100</photo>
  </functionality>
  <execution>
    <postscript />
  </execution>
  <comments>
    <en>

      Under this entry Epson's PPD files for their PostScript printers
      are hosted. PostScript printers are supported natively in Linux
      and Unix environments, so you only need the PPD file for your
      printer, no driver executables, to get access to all printing
      functionality. The PPD contains all information about properties
      and user-settable options which are specific to the printer and
      makes printing dialogs show these options and allow the user to
      control all the printer's functionality.&lt;p&gt;

      The PPDs only support the printing functionality of the
      printers. To use extra functionality, like scanning, faxing, ... you
      will perhaps need additional software.&lt;p&gt;

      See also &lt;a
      href=&quot;http://www.avasys.jp/english/linux_e/lpd_e.html&quot;&gt;for
      updated driver information for Epson printers and multi-function
      devices&lt;/a&gt;.

      Note that these printers work, like all other PostScript
      printers, with &lt;a
      href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=Postscript&quot;&gt;generic PostScript
      PPD files&lt;/a&gt;, but then you will not get access to all the
      printer specific functionality.&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</driver>
