<driver id="driver/pxljr">
 <name>pxljr</name>
 <url>http://hp-pxl-jetready.sourceforge.net/</url>
 <execution>
  <ijs />
  <prototype></prototype>
 </execution>
 <comments>
  <en>

    In contrary to HP&apos;s HPIJS this driver contributed by Hin-Tak
    Leung (also author of the drivers for Epson&apos;s EPL "L" laser
    printers) supports without any proprietary plug-ins all printout
    qualities which the Windows driver provides for the HP Color
    LaserJet 35xx/36xx. The development of this driver is not
    supported by HP, it is an independent project.&lt;p&gt;

    Cited from the driver&apos;s home page:&lt;p&gt;

    [...]&lt;p&gt;
    
    &lt;i&gt;PXLJR is an IJS-based driver for the HP JetReady 4.x
    protocol printer family (Color Laserjet 3500 and 3550) under linux
    and other unix-like systems. This effort is not endorsed by nor
    affiliated with HP.&lt;p&gt;

    It is licensed under the terms of GNU General Public
    License.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    [...]&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;i&gt;HPIJS/HPLIP also supports these two printers. Why are you
    "reinventing the wheel"?&lt;p&gt;

    HPIJS provides 2 printing modes:
    one color and one gray, corresponding to the
    max-compression/worst-quality setting of the HP driver under
    Windows. There are two more settings for better quality in the
    Windows driver. PXLJR provides these two additional settings, so
    there are a total of 6 printing modes. Also, the max-compression
    gray mode of PXLJR is 1.5 to 3 times faster.&lt;p&gt;

    One the other hand, PXLJR doesn't provide a full set of facilities
    like printer status report, etc. For other bells and whistles,
    please use HPLIP's toolbox instead. There is no conflict
    installing both HPIJS and PXLJR simultaneously.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    [...]&lt;p&gt;

    Note that this driver has two bugs:&lt;p&gt;

    The first bug is that double-sided printing (duplex) does not
    work. For this a &lt;a
    href="http://www.openprinting.org/download/printing/pxljr-patches/duplex.patch"&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt;
    from Till Kamppeter is a available.&lt;p&gt;

    The second bug is a problem of color output. In the draft and
    normal quality modes some color tones are not printed and come out
    white instead. The problem does not occur in the high quality
    mode. The bug was reported to the &lt;a
    href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/pxljr/+bug/228635"&gt;Ubuntu
    bug tracking system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;
					 
    Both bugs are reported to the driver's author.&lt;p&gt;

    As the PPD file is available on the driver&apos;s web site, we
    will not provide PPD files here at OpenPrinting. Note that
    there is currently only one PPD file, which serves for all
    supported printer models. The printers only differ in print speed
    and presence of an ethernet interface.&lt;p&gt;

    For extra functions like toner level and status checks use the
    CUPS backend of HPLIP ("&lt;tt&gt;hp:/...&lt;/tt&gt;" URI) and the
    "&lt;tt&gt;hp-toolbox&lt;/tt&gt;". There is no problem to use
    HPLIP together with this driver.&lt;p&gt;

  </en>
 </comments>
 <printers>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/HP-Color_LaserJet_3500</id>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/HP-Color_LaserJet_3550</id>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/HP-Color_LaserJet_3600</id>
  </printer>
 </printers>
</driver>
