<driver id="driver/rastertokmXXXXdl">
 <name>rastertokmXXXXdl</name>
 <url>http://printer.konicaminolta.com/support/index_ds.html</url>
 <supplier>KONICA MINOLTA</supplier>
 <manufacturersupplied>KONICA MINOLTA|Minolta</manufacturersupplied>
 <license>GPL</license>
 <freesoftware />
 <!--not "nonfreesoftware"-->
 <supportcontacts>
  <supportcontact level="voluntary" url="http://printer.konicaminolta.com/support/index_ds.html">KONICA MINOLTA Printer Support Site</supportcontact>
  <!--not level="commercial"-->
 </supportcontacts>
 <shortdescription>
  <en>
   Free software printer drivers for the magicolor DL series from
   KONICA MINOLTA
  </en>
 </shortdescription>
 <functionality>
  <maxresx>2400</maxresx>
  <maxresy>600</maxresy>
  <color />
  <text>100</text>
  <lineart>100</lineart>
  <graphics>100</graphics>
  <photo>100</photo>
  <load></load>
  <speed></speed>
 </functionality>
 <execution>
  <cups />
  <prototype></prototype>
 </execution>
 <comments>
  <en>

    Drivers for the KONICA MINOLTA magicolor DL series, supplied by
    KONICA MINOLTA.&lt;p&gt;

    The KONICA MINOLTA magicolor DL series are rather cheap color
    laser printers with a Zenographics-based protocol. Some of them
    are therefore also supported by the "foo2zjs" driver. Note that
    there is also a KONICA MINOLTA magicolor W series which has no
    Linux support from KONICA MINOLTA. At least some of them work with
    the "m2300w" and "m2400w" drivers.&lt;p&gt;

    The drivers which KONICA MINOLTA supplies for the magicolor DL
    series are entirely free software, there are no binary-only pieces
    inside. So you can compile, and optimize the driver for your
    system platform, security-audit the code and make the driver also
    part of a Linux distribution,&lt;p&gt;

    The drivers are CUPS raster drivers. So they need the CUPS
    libraries, and Ghostscript with the "cups" device built-in (for
    example ESP Ghostscript). PPD files come with the driver package,
    therefore no PPDs are available on OpenPrinting.&lt;p&gt;

    The drivers support all functionality of the printers except
    "EAIDC" (automatically adjust halftone during the jobs). Even
    color management is supported and appropriate ICC profiles are
    included in the driver package.&lt;p&gt;

    The KONICA MINOLTA magicolor 2300 DL is not officially supported
    but works with the driver and PPD file for the 2430 DL. Mote that
    there is also a Minolta magicolor 2300 DL (without "KONICA") which
    is similar but not exactly the same. If someone of you has this
    model, please report here whether it also works.&lt;p&gt;

    To obtain the drivers, go to the site mentioned here, choose your
    printer model under "Color Laser", and then choose "Linux" under
    "Drivers, PPDs, &amp; Utilities". You can also find the drivers &lt;a
    href="http://www.openprinting.org/download/printing/konicaminolta/"&gt;here
    on OpenPrinting&lt;/a&gt;, but be aware that they are perhaps
    not up-to-date.&lt;p&gt;

  </en>
 </comments>
 <printers>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/KONICA_MINOLTA-magicolor_2300_DL</id>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/KONICA_MINOLTA-magicolor_2430_DL</id>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/KONICA_MINOLTA-magicolor_5430_DL</id>
  </printer>
  <printer>
   <id>printer/KONICA_MINOLTA-magicolor_5440_DL</id>
  </printer>
 </printers>
</driver>
