<printer id="printer/Brother-HL-2035">
  <make>Brother</make>
  <model>HL-2035</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>1200</x>
        <y>600</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://solutions.brother.com/linux/en_us/index.html</url>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
    <pjl />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <usb>
      <ieee1284>MFG:Brother;CMD:PJL,HBP;MDL:HL-2030 series;CLS:PRINTER;</ieee1284>
      <commandset>PJL,HBP</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Brother</manufacturer>
      <model>HL-2030 series</model>
    </usb>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>B</functionality>
  <driver>hl1250</driver>
  <drivers>
    <driver>
      <id>Brother's HL-2030 driver for CUPS</id>
      <comments>
        <en>

          This gives a choice of 300dpi, 600dpi (default) or
          HQ1200dpi. The test page under the default 600dpi is much
          better. This test page (Ubuntu/GPL Ghostscript Version: 3010
          Revision: 861) has six lines as border. One gets six lines
          at top and bottom and five of each side. Thus the printing
          zone now leaves out 4 mm at top and bottom and 6 mm on both
          sides.

	</en>
      </comments>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>gimp-print</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>gutenprint</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>hl1250</id>
      <comments>
        <en>

	  Under Ubuntu 8.04, the printer is immediately recognized as
	  &quot;usb://Brother HL-2030 series&quot; The configuration
	  system (system-config-printer 0.7.81 from Red Hat, Inc.
	  &lt;a
	  href=&quot;http://cyberelk.net/tim/software/system-config-printer/)&quot;&gt;http://cyberelk.net/tim/software/system-config-printer/)&lt;/a&gt;
	  proposes the choice of a lot of different drivers but
	  recommends &quot;Brother HL-2060 Foomatic/hl1250&quot; This
	  gives a choice of 300DPI, 600DPI or 1200x600DPI (default 300
	  dpi). The test page under the default 300DPI is reasonably
	  good. This test page (Ubuntu/GPL Ghostscript Version: 3010
	  Revision: 861) has six lines as border. From these I get
	  only three lines above and five down. The six lines are
	  visible on the sides with equal margin outside. As such, the
	  printing zone seems to leave out 4 mm above and 8 or 9 mm at
	  bottom and 4 mm or less on the sides.

	</en>
      </comments>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>hpijs-pcl5e</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>lj4dith</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>lj5gray</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>ljet4</id>
    </driver>
  </drivers>
  <contrib_url>http://www.meeus-d.be/linux/brohl2035.html</contrib_url>
  <comments>
    <en>

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;User comment:&lt;/b&gt; I bought this printer
      today (22-9-2008) and I am using it at home to print text. I did
      not test all its possibilities and I am not going to. Therefore
      I choose &quot;Mostly&quot;, but maybe it deserves more. When
      printing photographs à HQ1200dpi you sometimes get an second
      page stating &quot;There is not enough memory... The printer has
      printed at a reduced resolution&quot;. This is funny because a
      GDI printer is supposed to have a little memory because the job
      is done by the computer. But if you really wanted to print
      photos, you would buy a good colour printer. Let me say that it
      is quite noisy when printing but that this is not an issue
      because it very soon goes back to sleep and that it is a
      noiseless sleep. I find it a real advantage that it has a true
      closed paper tray (250 sheets). Some printers in that category
      have a protruding paper tray (for 100 à 150 sheets) in the good
      old deskjet style. A closed tray under the printer lets no dust
      in and takes less valuable real estate (as they say in American
      computer magazines) from your desk.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Brother proposes its own software on the page &lt;a
      href=&quot;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/en_us/index.html&quot;&gt;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/en_us/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.
      Under HL-2035, it sends back to HL-2030. I downloaded
      &lt;code&gt;brhl2030lpr-2.0.1-1.i386.deb&lt;/code&gt; and
      installed it by simply double clicking it (not in a terminal and
      not with the suggested &lt;code&gt;--force-all
      --force-architecture&lt;/code&gt;).  I downloaded
      &lt;code&gt;cupswrapperHL2030-2.0.1-2.i386.deb&lt;/code&gt; and
      installed it by simply double clicking it, but that gave an
      error.  I then read and applied the &quot;pre-required
      procedures&quot; for Ubuntu 8.04 on Brother's web site,
      installed again (again without the suggested
      &lt;code&gt;--force-all --force-architecture&lt;/code&gt;) and
      that was successful. I choose the &lt;code&gt;Brother HL2030 for
      CPUs&lt;/code&gt; driver, that I suppose was the one I just
      installed with the Debian package.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update.&lt;/b&gt; After I did this, I
      discovered in the forum that Debian packages are available in
      the Multiverse repository for Ubuntu 8.04. These are supposed to
      be improved versions from Brother's. Therefore, under
      Ubuntu (and maybe with Debian or other Debian derivatives),
      simply read &lt;a
      href=&quot;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/BrotherDriverPackaging&quot;&gt;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/BrotherDriverPackaging&lt;/a&gt;
      and install the appropriate packages. Through Synaptic,
      selecting &lt;code&gt;brother-cups-wrapper-laser&lt;/code&gt; is
      sufficient, the lpr stuff being installed as a dependency. This
      uninstalls Brother's packages. This leaves the printer
      without any driver during installation and it could be necessary
      to reactivate the printer after installation.&lt;/p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: Toner TN-2005 (up to 1500 pages) ; Drum
      DR-2005 (up to 12 000 pages)&lt;/p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
