<printer id="printer/Brother-HL-2140">
  <make>Brother</make>
  <model>HL-2140</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>1200</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.brother.com/</url>
  <lang>
    <postscript level="2" />
    <pcl level="5e" />
    <pjl />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <usb>
      <commandset>PJL,HBP</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Brother</manufacturer>
      <model>HL-2140 series</model>
    </usb>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>B</functionality>
  <driver>hpijs-pcl5e</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    Brother publishes proprietary Linux drivers for CUPS and LPD for
    most of their laser printers and multi-function devices, including
    SANE drivers for the scanners. They can be downloaded free of
    charge on their &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/en_us/&quot;&gt;Linux driver
    page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

    Some comments of a user's experience:&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date : 09-03-2008 &lt;/b&gt; I am using Kubuntu 8.04.1
    LTS. The printer was Auto-Detected. I have not had to manually
    install any drivers. The driver automatically being used is
    &quot;Brother HL-2060 Foomatic/HL1250&quot;. Prints clean at 300dpi. Prints
    very good at 600dpi. I tried to print at 1200x600dpi. It gave me
    blank pages. Excellent TEXT printer. Okay Graphical Printer. I
    believe that if we can figure out a way to print at higher
    resolution, graphical printing quality may improve!&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;b&gt;Date : September 28th, 2008&lt;/b&gt; Works with Ubuntu
    8.04 with full support (even 1200x600 dpi). For having this
    working properly, first install the LPR driver found here &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/sol/printer/linux/lpr_drivers.html.&quot;&gt;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/sol/printer/linux/lpr_drivers.html.&lt;/a&gt;
    Then create a directory for the PPD file with&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;sudo mkdir /usr/share/cups/model&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    Then install the CUPS driver wrapper found here &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/sol/printer/linux/cups_drivers.html&quot;&gt;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/sol/printer/linux/cups_drivers.html&lt;/a&gt;
    with dpkg.&lt;p&gt;

    After that, CUPS enables to set power savings and correct 1200 dpi
    resolution. Enjoy!&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;b&gt;Date: November 9, 2008&lt;/b&gt; I use CentOS 5.2, and I
    was not able to find a straight linux printer driver on the noted
    web page.  However, on the CUPS driver page, there were links to
    the CUPS driver and the CUPS wrapper driver pages, both of which
    downloaded in .rpm format and installed perfectly and worked right
    away.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;b&gt;Date: January 04, 2009&lt;/b&gt; I use Mandriva 2008
    Spring and Mandriva 2009. Using the above links I found the RPM
    drivers AND wrappeers and they both installed fine. I then plugged
    in the printer via USB and it was auto-detected and works
    amazingly well.&lt;p&gt;

    Again, Mandriva just seems to &quot;work&quot; in most cases, no &quot;mkdir
    blah&quot;, or &quot;chmod this file&quot;, or even &quot;sudo run this or that
    command&quot;... just install both rpm's and
    autdo-detect... DONE!&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;b&gt;08 Feb 2009&lt;/b&gt; Kubuntu 8.10 - The printer was
    recognized automatically as &quot;HL2140-0series&quot; and printing would
    cause data to be sent to printer (its blue light blinked) but
    nothing printed. Downloaded lpr and cups .deb packages from
    Brother (use &quot;search&quot; on their Web site, Linux drivers are not
    linked from the printer downloads page.) Follow Brother's
    instructions carefully before installing the DEB package; you have
    to manually create one directory (&quot;sudo mkdir
    /usr/share/cups/model&quot;). When it is working the printer shows up
    as &quot;HL2140&quot; instead of &quot;HL2140-series&quot;.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;b&gt;26 Feb 2009&lt;/b&gt; I want to re-enforce the previous note someone else made. &lt;br /&gt;

    1) Plug in the printer to the computer. Ignore all the prompts, hit cancel, etc.&lt;br /&gt;

    2) Download the LPR and CUPS deb files from this link (or search
    for them on the site): &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/en_us/download_prn.html#HL-2140&quot;&gt;http://solutions.brother.com/linux/en_us/download_prn.html#HL-2140&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br
    /&gt;

    3) &lt;tt&gt;sudo mkdir /usr/share/cups/model&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

    4) &lt;tt&gt;sudo dpkg -i --force-all --force-architecture [the two debs you
    downloaded]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;THE FORCE SWITCHES ARE VITAL FOR 64 BIT
    MACHINES!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;


    5)Profit. The printer should work and show up as &quot;HL2140&quot;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: TN330 or TN360 toner, DR360 drum&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
