<printer id="printer/Canon-BJC-55">
  <make>Canon</make>
  <model>BJC-55</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet/>
    <color/>
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>720</x>
        <y>360</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
    <consumables>
      <comments>
        <en>1 CMY and 1 small black or 1 large black cartridge</en>
      </comments>
    <!--one or more "partno" elements.--></consumables>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.ccsi.canon.com/bjc/bjc55/</url>
  <lang>
    <proprietary/><!--no pjl-->
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <parallel>
      <manufacturer>Canon</manufacturer>
      <model>BJC-55</model>
    </parallel>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>B</functionality>
  <driver>gutenprint</driver>
  <!--not "unverified"-->
  <contrib_url>http://www.physiol.usyd.edu.au/daved/linux/bjc-80.html</contrib_url>
  <comments>
    <en>Ultra-portable printer, smallest printer I have
ever seen and it prints &quot;Perfectly&quot; with free
software. The scanning facility with an optional
scanning cartridge is not supported by
free software drivers.&lt;p&gt;
 
USB and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.physiol.usyd.edu.au/daved/linux/bjc-80.html&quot;&gt;IRDA&lt;/a&gt; ports (all working), no parallel port,
integrated rechargeable battery, due to its size it
does not provide an automatic sheet feeder. Use
the somewhat bigger BJC-80/85 printers if you need
automatic sheet feeding. The printout quality and
the drivers are the same. Note that the cartridges
are rather small, and so the expenses per page are
probably very high. So you should buy this printer
only if you really need to print when you are on
travel. In addition, the resolution is lower than
the resolution of most modern desktop inkjets.&lt;p&gt;

The Canons are the best solution for portable
printing with free software. They are small and
light, have a reasonable resolution and speed and
their printing capabilities are fully supported.
The portables of HP are rather heavy and the
Brother MP-21C (PCMCIA) is a &quot;Paperweight&quot;.&lt;p&gt;

To get the best quality out of it for all kinds of
printing jobs (text, drawings, photos), use the
&quot;gutenprint&quot;
(former Gimp-Print) driver. Then you
get photo printouts with a quality close to the 
quality of the Epson Stylus Color 440. The &quot;bjc600&quot;
works well for text and drawings, but has problems
with photos.&lt;p&gt;

The BJC-50 is the same printer but with parallel port
instead of USB.</en>
  </comments>
</printer>
