<printer id="printer/Epson-Stylus_Photo_RX500">
  <make>Epson</make>
  <model>Stylus Photo RX500</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>5760</x>
        <y>1440</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <lang>
    <escp />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <commandset>ESCPL2,BDC,D4</commandset>
      <description>EPSON Stylus Photo RX500</description>
      <manufacturer>EPSON</manufacturer>
      <model>Stylus Photo RX500</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>D</functionality>
  <driver>gutenprint</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    Multi-function device: Printer, Scanner, Copier.&lt;p&gt;

    The printing engine of this device is most probably the same as of
    the Epson Stylus Photo R300, for which basic support is available
    in Gimp-Print 5.0.x.  Fine tuning, testing, and support for
    printing on CDs still has to be done.&lt;p&gt;

    This printer has slots for all common types of flash memory
    cards. so one can print photos without PC direcly from the
    camera's card. The front panel has a graphical user interface
    which gives many options for printing from photo cards. Photo
    download works with kernel 2.4.21 or later. The memory card can be
    simply mounted as a USB-mass-storage device then. You can also
    scan documents or photos onto a memory card, for example for usage
    with a PDA.&lt;p&gt;

    6-color CMYKcm printing, printing on inkjet-printable CDs and DVDs
    possible (not yet supported by Gimp-Print).&lt;p&gt;

    Scanning should work as described for the Epson Stylus CX3200 and
    CX5200, best with kernel 2.4.21 or later. To make the &quot;epson&quot;
    backend of &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.sane-project.org/&quot;&gt;SANE&lt;/a&gt; recognizing
    this device, you have to add a line like&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;usb 0x4b8 0x805&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    to the &lt;tt&gt;/etc/sane.d/epson.conf&lt;/tt&gt; file where the
    two hexadecimal numbers are the vendor and product IDs of your
    scanner. You find the actual IDs in
    &lt;tt&gt;/proc/bus/usb/devices&lt;/tt&gt;. Search for an entry
    for an Epson device (the model name can be different to &quot;CX5400&quot;
    as often the Epson devices report their japanese market name) and
    in the line beginning with &quot;&lt;tt&gt;P&lt;/tt&gt;&quot; directly above
    the line with the manufacturer name you find the hexadecimal
    vendor and product IDs.&lt;p&gt;

    Copying should just work with the front panel of the
    device.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: 6 separately exchangeable ink cartridges&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
