<printer id="printer/Epson-Stylus_Color_760">
  <make>Epson</make>
  <model>Stylus Color 760</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>720</x>
        <y>1440</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://support.epson.com/hardware/printer/inkjet/sc760_/index.html</url>
  <lang>
    <escp />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <parallel>
      <commandset>ESCPL2,BDC,D4</commandset>
      <description>EPSON Stylus COLOR 760</description>
      <manufacturer>EPSON</manufacturer>
      <model>Stylus COLOR 760</model>
    </parallel>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>gutenprint</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>Note that you *MUST* turn off the so-called &quot;D4&quot; mode of the parallel interface of this printer in order to get it to work.
To turn off the D4 mode, follow these instructions (from &lt;a href=&quot;http://files.support.epson.com/pdf/sc760_/sc760_f1.txt&quot;&gt;http://files.support.epson.com/pdf/sc760_/sc760_f1.txt&lt;/a&gt;):
&lt;p&gt; 
  Turn on the printer while holding down the Cleaning button (under the inkdrop icons)
  The paper-out light (under the &quot;paper&quot; icons) will start blinking.
  Release the Cleaning button and *IMMEDIATELY* press and hold the Load/Eject button (under the &quot;paper&quot; icon) and hold it for about 20 seconds.
  The Paper Out, Color Ink Out, and Black Ink Out LEDs will light.
  Release the Load/Eject button.
  Press the Cleaning Button until the Black Ink Out LED lights. This means D4 mode is off.
  Press the Load/Eject button and you're done.
 &lt;p&gt;
I used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lcewww.et.tudelft.nl/~haver/linux/epson.html&quot;&gt;epson740 upp ghostscript driver&lt;/a&gt;, and wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://csl.cse.ucsc.edu/~ben/magicfilter/stylus760-filter&quot;&gt;quick magicfilter config (stylus760-filter), available here&lt;/a&gt; to use that driver. Then I plopped it into /etc/magicfilter, ran /usr/sbin/magicfilterconfig, and chose the stylus760 filter.
&lt;p&gt;Everything works except I couldn't figure out how to convince magicfilter to add an EOF character after every print-job, so the pages are not ejected by themselves. Sorry :) Hopefully someone else can figure this out.

I've added another magicfilter, that I have written, it fixes the eject bug at the cost of removing recode support, &lt;a href=&quot;http://c-cc.co.uk/hosted/epson_760/stylus760-filter&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;------------
&lt;p&gt;Actually it works great for me even with D4 mode in auto mode (the default).
&lt;p&gt;
Ed: Probably works best with the stp driver.&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: cartridge&lt;p&gt;</en>
  </comments>
</printer>
