<printer id="printer/Hitachi-DDP_70_with_MicroPress">
  <make>Hitachi</make>
  <model>DDP 70 (with MicroPress)</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>600</x>
        <y>600</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.hitachi-koki.com/</url>
  <lang>
    <postscript level="3" />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>Postscript</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    I used the original PPD (supposedly just written to support MacOS
    and MS Win printing) with CUPS, which can use LPD as a backend to
    send the print data out. All options can be used: select 1 of 5
    trays; choose A4, Letter, A3, A3 FullBleed etc.; duplex printing;
    print on forms; 1-up, 2-up,...16-up; use watermarks; RipNHold; 2
    output destinations with face up or down each etc.&lt;p&gt;

    The device at the moment is run by a (MS Windows NT Server based)
    Harlequin RIP which is upgraded by the MicroPress software; after
    you've sent the job to the (NT-) RIP (which sends the binary
    TIFF-like data to the output device), the RIP can keep your RIPped
    data in the form of bitmapped pages for further manipulation:
    preview, delete pages; insert pages from a different job; merge
    jobs; rearrange the order of pages; use different imposition
    schemes; delete areas on pages or move, invert, scale or rotate
    them; paginate the pages etc.&lt;p&gt;

    After the manipulations there is no need of re-RIPping; the
    printers start printing immediately putting out paper. The system
    is used for purposes like &quot;print on Demand&quot; (PoD),
    personalised printing, print variable data, 1:1 marketing, jobs
    that often need a re-print with some minor changes in between
    print runs (when it is much more expensive to do the
    time-consuming process to re-RIP the complete data again and
    again).  It is a system for professional digital printing capable
    of doing up to 400.000 prints per month per unit.&lt;p&gt;

    The system is capable of running as a print cluster of up to 12
    connected printer units which can share a huge job amongst
    themselves or work on different ones each. (The maximum cluster
    gives you 840 ppm and a monthly volume of 4.8 million
    prints).&lt;p&gt;

    (tested by Kurt Pfeifle)&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: toner&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
