<printer id="printer/HP-DeskJet_932C">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>DeskJet 932C</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet/>
    <color/>
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>2400</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
    <consumables>
      <comments>
        <en>cartridge</en>
      </comments>
    <!--one or more "partno" elements.--></consumables>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.hp.com/cposupport/eschome.html</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3"/><!--no pjl-->
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
  <!--no known parport probe information--></autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>hpijs</driver>
  <!--affiliate keys; modify and face my wrath!-->
  <buyit>67782</buyit><!--no "contrib_url"-->
  <comments>
    <en>

    For basic printing functionality use the &lt;a 
    href=&quot;http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;HPIJS 
    driver &lt;/a&gt;. For advanced functionality such
    as printer status and maintenance features, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;
    HPLIP driver&lt;/a&gt; (which includes HPIJS). &lt;p&gt;

    The best output one gets with HP&apos;s HPIJS 1.3 or newer. If you
    cannot update to HPIJS 1.3 for some reason, you can also use HPIJS
    1.2.2 with the patches from Matthias Bunte and Richard
    Spencer-Smith (&quot;hpijs-rss&quot;). The Gimp-Print driver also
    works (Model setting: &quot;pcl-900&quot;), but only up to 600
    dpi.&lt;p&gt;

    *****User Report*******&lt;p&gt;

    I used the &quot;DeskJet 550C/560C/6xxC&quot; driver from
    RedHat&apos;s Printtool. I also enabled the fix for stair
    steping. According to the webpage, it does up to 2400x2400 under
    windows, but that is because of the PhotoREt III color layering
    technology, which from what I understand, just makes the ink
    droplets smaller.  The GS driver limits it to 600x600, I
    believe. I hope all the info I entered here is correct, please
    someone correct me if I&apos;m wrong.&lt;p&gt;

    So, like most recent HP models, this printer qualifies for, at
    best, &quot;Mostly&quot;. Most of the best printing modes
    aren&apos;t really supported properly, because HP doesn&apos;t
    document their newer printers.&lt;p&gt;

    *****Different User*******&lt;p&gt;

    I find it works perfectly on black text using this driver,hwoever
    color horrible. Color is better using the &quot;500/6xxC&quot;
    series driver, but black text is just a wee bit off at the very
    bottom of the page.  Using the 800 series drivers sends the color
    to the left, and is unable to print thr 1&quot; margin at the
    bottom.  Someone needs to add a decent driver... I want to print
    photos!&lt;p&gt;

    *****Different User*******&lt;p&gt;

    I just got the new &quot;880C/882C/895C&quot; driver, and I think
    it gives a slightly crisper image than the 550C, and so far it
    works well.&lt;p&gt;

    *****Different User*******&lt;p&gt;

    &quot;stp&quot; is slow but better than other drivers for
    photos. However the quality is still very poor as compared to a
    PostScript printer. I would recommend **not** purchasing this
    printer (or most other HP inkjets if you want to print photos) for
    use with Linux. I tried emailing HP several times because of their
    claims of supporting Linux, but never received a response. They
    also claim printing support on sourceforge yet I found none from
    HP.&lt;p&gt;

    *****Different User*******&lt;p&gt;

    &quot;hpdj&quot; driver works well and is included with debian;
    However, the &quot;stp&quot; driver provides cleaner results. I
    printed a photograph in windows and linux, unfortunately the
    colors and resolution in windows were both highly
    superior.. although the quality in linux was acceptable for
    draft-quality work.
    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>


