<printer id="printer/HP-DeskJet_5670">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>DeskJet 5670</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet/>
    <color/>
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>4800</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
    <consumables>
      <comments>
        <en>One Color(CMY) + one Black(K) or Photo (cmK)</en>
      </comments>
    <!--one or more "partno" elements.--></consumables>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://products.hp-at-home.com/products/detail.php?prodnum=C6487C</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3e"/>
  <!--no pjl--><!--No "text"?--></lang>
  <autodetect>
    <parallel>
      <commandset>MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,DYN,DESKJET</commandset>
      <description>hp deskjet 5670</description>
      <manufacturer>hp</manufacturer>
      <model>deskjet 5670</model>
    </parallel>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>hpijs</driver>
  <!--no "contrib_url"-->
  <comments>
    <en>

    Duplex unit optional, connection via parallel port and USB&lt;p&gt;

    For basic printing functionality use the &lt;a 
    href=&quot;http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;HPIJS 
    driver &lt;/a&gt;. For advanced functionality such
    as printer status and maintenance features, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;
    HPLIP driver&lt;/a&gt; (which includes HPIJS). &lt;p&gt;

    The best printout quality you will get with the &quot;hpijs&quot;
    driver, provided by &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://hplip.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;HP&lt;/a&gt;
    (compatible to the HP DeskJet 990C), especially the 1200-dpi high
    resolution mode gives excellent photo quality (the rendered bitmap
    is 1200x1200 dpi, but the printer hardware does an interpolation
    then and prints with the printer&apos;s highest resolution). Also
    the Gimp-Print driver is reported to work (Model setting:
    &quot;pcl-900&quot;).&lt;p&gt;

    When used with HP&apos;s &quot;hpijs&quot; driver, this printer
    auto-detects the paper type and ink cartridge type and does
    appropriate dithering and colour adjustment internally, controlled
    by the hardware. So when GhostScript with the &quot;hpijs&quot;
    driver only renders the image with 300 or 600 dpi, higher
    resolutions are used for the internal dithering. So if you insert
    photo paper, the printer will print in photo quality, no paper
    type choice in the driver&apos;s options is needed. There is also
    a special high resolution mode where the image is rendered in 1200
    dpi and interpolated to 4800x1200 dpi by the hardware, without
    paper detection, intended for photo paper only.&lt;p&gt;

    Current border-less (full bleed) support is 3-sided for paper sizes
    Oufuku-Hagaki or smaller. The HPIJS team is currently evaluating
    4-sided large paper size (A4/Letter) or smaller full bleed support
    and expect to address this issue in a future release.

    The duplex unit does not work with Gimp-Print, use
    &quot;hpijs&quot;, &quot;cdj970&quot; or &quot;pcl3&quot; instead.

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>

