<printer id="printer/HP-LaserJet_1012">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>LaserJet 1012</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser/>
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>600</x>
        <y>600</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
    <consumables>
      <comments>
        <en>Toner and drum in one cartridge (18000 pages)</en>
      </comments>
    </consumables>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.shopping.hp.com/cgi-bin/hpdirect/shopping/scripts/product_detail/product_detail_view.jsp?BV_SessionID=@@@@2054406155.1109190045@@@@&amp;BV_EngineID=ccdladddmehjidmcfngcfkmdflldfgf.0&amp;landing=null&amp;category=laserjets_bw&amp;subcat1=entry_level&amp;product_code=Q2461A%23ABA&amp;catLevel=3</url>
  <lang>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <parallel>
      <commandset>FastRaster</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Hewlett-Packard</manufacturer>
      <model>hp LaserJet 1012</model>
    </parallel>
    <usb>
    </usb>
  </autodetect>
  <driver>hpijs</driver>
  <functionality>B</functionality>
  <comments>
    <en>
    For basic printing functionality use the &lt;a 
    href=&quot;http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;HPIJS 
    driver &lt;/a&gt;. For advanced functionality such
    as printer status and maintenance features, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;
    HPLIP driver&lt;/a&gt; (which includes HPIJS). &lt;p&gt;
    
    With hpijs 0.9.x HP introduces support for FastRaster products on Linux!    There is a 600x1200 path that we can not support due to IP issues, but other than the one print mode, as of the release of hpijs 0.9.x, the HP LaserJet 1012 is now supported.&lt;p&gt;

    Cheap, compact desktop laser printer, foldable tray for 150
    sheets, A4/Letter/Legal, up to 14 pages/min. Somewhat faster than
    the LaserJet 1010, "Fastres 1200" resolution enhancement.&lt;p&gt;

    HP classifies this printer as "host-based" whereas they claim the
    HP LaserJet 1015 to understand PCL 5e. But the HP LaserJet 1010
    and 1012 seem to understand a stripped-down (raster-graphics only,
    no text) variant of PCL 5e.&lt;p&gt;

    Rick Richardson (rickr at mn dot rr dot com), author of the
    &quot;foo2zjs&quot; driver (driver for the HP LaserJet 1000/1005),
    has examined the output of the Windows driver for this printer and
    found out that the language looks like PJL + PCL 6 (see report
    on the HP forum on OpenPrinting).&lt;p&gt;

    Adam (madaman at web dot de) reports on the HP forum on
    OpenPrinting that the HP LaserJet 1010 works for him with all
    raster drivers for the HP LaserJet 1100 ("hpijs",
    "ljet4", "lj4dith", "gimp-print"). Adam tried also PCL-6 drivers
    ("lj5gray"/"lj5mono", "pxlmono") but without success.&lt;p&gt;

    Unfortunately, the new LaserJet 1010/1012 series seems not to
    be absolutely compatible with older HP printers or it has a
    firmware bug. Sometimes it happens that the printer stops working
    and reports the error "&lt;tt&gt;Unsupported Personality:
    PCL&lt;/tt&gt;". It only continues working when one kills the job
    and power-cycles the printer.&lt;p&gt;

    The problem of the "&lt;tt&gt;Unsupported Personality:
    PCL&lt;/tt&gt;" was finally solved by Carl Michal (michal at
    physics dot ubc dot ca). By analyzing the output of the Windows
    driver he found out that after the BeginSession operator in the
    beginning of a PCL 6 job a special sequence of 8 bytes has to be
    added. He added it by a filter to the output of GhostScript's
    "pxlmono" driver and from then on the printer worked.&lt;p&gt;
    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
