<printer id="printer/HP-LaserJet_4L">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>LaserJet 4L</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>300</x>
        <y>300</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.hp.com/cposupport/prodhome/lj4l.html</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="5e" />
    <pjl />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <parallel>
      <commandset>HP ENHANCED PCL5,PJL</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Hewlett-Packard</manufacturer>
      <model>LaserJet 4L</model>
    </parallel>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>ljet4</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    For basic printing functionality use the PPD from this site. For
    advanced functionality such as printer status and maintenance
    features, use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hplipopensource.com/&quot;&gt;
    HPLIP driver&lt;/a&gt; (which includes HPIJS). &lt;p&gt;

    This printer is of around 1995, it was discontinued some years
    ago. The HP website carries little to no information about the
    printer. ZDNet still has spec's if someone needs them.&lt;p&gt;

    The HP 4L is the Model C2003A.  Neither ID is listed as supported
    by HPLIP.  The series included the 4L, 4L Pro, 4Lc, and
    4mL. Presumably, any of these uses the same driver.&lt;p&gt;

    The toner cartridge is HP 92274A (No. 74A) and is available for
    less than 20USD via eBay or a little more via other
    sources. Refills are of course cheaper. A brand new HP cartridge
    with super fine toner costs more than the printer.&lt;p&gt;

    The LaserJet 4L printer provides 300 dots per inch description
    resolution, plus built-in Resolution Enhancement technology (REt)
    and built-in Memory Enhancement technology with a throughput of up
    to 4 pages per minute. It has the ability to scale fonts, enhanced
    PCL 5 Language, EconoMode printing, an Instant-On Fuser, and the
    HP-GL/2 enhancement for plotter output.&lt;p&gt;

    Slow by today's standards but quite a nice compact LaserJet 10
    years ago.&lt;p&gt;

    Although the driver may work perfectly, toner is abysmally
    expensive now. Time to get a new laser printer.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: Toner ($70?)&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
