<printer id="printer/HP-LaserJet_1000">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>LaserJet 1000</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser/><!--not "color"-->
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>600</x>
        <y>600</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
    <consumables>
      <comments>
        <en>Cartridge containing toner and imaging drum</en>
      </comments>
    <!--one or more "partno" elements.--></consumables>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.hp.com/cposupport/prodhome/hplaserjet45675.html
</url>
  <lang>
    <proprietary/>
  <!--no pjl--><!--No "text"?--></lang>
  <autodetect>
  <!--no known parport probe information--></autodetect>
  <functionality>D</functionality>
  <driver>pbmtozjs</driver>
  <!--no "contrib_url"-->
  <comments>
    <en>

    GDI printer, which does not understand any standard language. Works
    with the &quot;pbmtozjs&quot; driver from Szalai Robert.&lt;p&gt;

    PCL is only implemented in the Windows driver, to support DOS
    applications in the DOS box of Windows. The printer has only 1 MB
    of RAM and 32 kb (!) of ROM and is USB only. &lt;p&gt;

    HP tries to enter the super-low-cost-disposable-printer market
    with this model. It costs only around 250 bucks.&lt;p&gt;

    The firmware of the printer must be uploaded after turning
    it on. Do not use the firmware on the CD supplied with the
    printer, download the current Windows driver for the printer from
    HP&apos;s web site, and extract the firmware file from it with
    &quot;&lt;tt&gt;unzip&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;, then you can send it to
    the printer with a simple &quot;&lt;tt&gt;cat&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;
    command. Here are instructions which were posted on the &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.linuxprinting.org/newsportal/article.php3?id=2347&amp;group=linuxprinting.hp.general&quot;&gt;HP
    forum&lt;/a&gt; of this site:&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
   1. Get new firmware from HP site
   (this is bloat download ~12MB but we need only ~115kB from it)

   ftp://ftp.hp.com/pub/softlib/software1/lj1488/lj-1145-2/lj1488en.exe

   2. extract sihp1000.img from it.

   # unzip lj1488en.exe sihp1000.img

   3. power printer and ...

   # cat sihp1000.img &gt; /dev/usb/lp0
    &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;

    Szalai Robert (szalai at ktk dot bme dot hu), the
    author of the "pbmtozjs" driver posted the following on the HP forum
    of this site:&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;i&gt;Just few words about the printer.  I think LaserJet 1000
    is a very odd printer. It has a very small ROM, so after you
    switched it on, you must download its firmware. Hopefully it can
    be done easiliy. The firmware can be found on HP's driver CD-ROM
    in the &lt;tt&gt;sihp1000.img&lt;/tt&gt; file and it must be sent
    simply to the printer. (e.g.: &quot;&lt;tt&gt;lpr
    sihp1000.img&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;). The firmware supports PJL, so you
    can use &lt;tt&gt;foomatic-getpjloptions&lt;/tt&gt;. Unfortunately
    after using PJL the printer behaves like
    &lt;tt&gt;/dev/null&lt;/tt&gt;, and does not print anything. I
    think the Windows driver uses PJL, as well, because some
    parameters such as print density cannot be controlled through the
    ZJ-stream.&lt;p&gt;

    The printing goes through ZJS format, which was developed by
    Zenographics Inc.  I think there are some other printers which use
    this format, but I do not have information which they are. There
    is a downloadable windows driver at &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://ddk.zeno.com/&quot;&gt;http://ddk.zeno.com/&lt;/a&gt;
    which I have used by writing the driver. The &quot;magic&quot;
    constants in the source were obtained by analyzing the output of
    the Windows driver.&lt;p&gt;

    The capabilities of the driver are very limited, because I&apos;m
    not able to use the printer&apos;s PJL language. Currently it
    supports only A4 paper, but this can be improved. Unfortunalely
    the paper size cannot be specified directly as a GhostScript
    parameter, such as &quot;&lt;tt&gt;-sPAPERSIZE=a4&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;
    because it will produce too large bitmaps. Instead, I recommend
    the use of &quot;&lt;tt&gt;-g4736x6817&lt;/tt&gt;&quot; option at
    600 dpi, at which the driver is currently working. The size of the
    image is very importortant, because if it does not meet the
    specified paper size, the printer will print blank pages until
    there is paper available.&lt;p&gt;
 
    The printer supports two resolutions: 300dpi and 600dpi, toner
    saving mode (ECONOMODE) and resolution enhancement technology
    (RET) which will be soon implemented into the driver. Currently it
    works at 600dpi, RET, no ECONOMODE.&lt;p&gt;

    The speed is the same as under Windows (approx. 10 pages/min).
    The biggest problem with the printer, that I couldn't modify the
    print density, because of PJL&apos;s misbehaviour. Currently it is
    unconvenient to use it through the command line, but I think
    somebody could make it automatic by integrating it into
    Foomatic. If you would like to update the printer database, I
    would recommed to rate the printer as "Partilally"
    working. Hopefully soon it will change to "Mostly".&lt;p&gt;

    Until the end of September I will make the driver available on our
    departmental home page, and than you can mirror it as you
    want.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/i&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
