<printer id="printer/HP-LaserJet_3150">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>LaserJet 3150</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>600</x>
        <y>600</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.hp.com/cposupport/eschome.html</url>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <ieee1284>MANUFACTURER:Hewlett-Packard;COMMAND SET:HP GDI,ECP18;MODEL:HP LaserJet 3150;CLASS:PRINTER;DESCRIPTION:Hewlett-Packard LaserJet 3150 MFP;</ieee1284>
      <commandset>HP GDI,ECP18</commandset>
      <description>Hewlett-Packard LaserJet 3150 MFP</description>
      <manufacturer>Hewlett-Packard</manufacturer>
      <model>HP LaserJet 3150</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>F</functionality>
  <contrib_url>/download/printing/hplj_3100_3150/</contrib_url>
  <comments>
    <en>
    Multifunction device - copier/scanner/fax/etc.&lt;p&gt;

    PCL 4 emulation appears to be host-based.&lt;p&gt;

    Not usable with free software: an HP tech support person told that
    half of the 3100's functionality is handled by the
    Windows-only drivers. Thus, even if you were on a Windows machine
    and go to the DOS prompt, doing &quot;DIR &amp;gt; LPT1:&quot;
    will fail; everything has to go through the windows
    drivers. (sigh)&lt;p&gt;

    According to the &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://hpoj.sourceforge.net/suplist.shtml&quot;&gt;hpoj
    project&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;i&gt;...if you have a LaserJet 3150 connected to an HP
    JetDirect 70X/170X/300X/500X with firmware x.08.xx or later, you
    can scan using the JetDirect's embedded web
    server.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    So this is a multifunction device that only scans!&lt;p&gt;

    If you have the luxury of a seperate MS Windows box, you can share
    the printer in the following manner:&lt;p&gt;
 
    After installing the normal drivers and JetSuite (HP software),
    add yet another printer. Use the LPT1: port and HP LasertJet II as
    the driver, then share this printer. You can now access this share
    via Linux as an SMB client; use the vanilla &quot;laserjet&quot;
    driver. The PCL emulation will complain, though the printout is
    fine thus far. You can turn off the complaints by editing your
    $WINDIR\JETSUITE.INI and in the &quot;[PCLEmulation]&quot;
    section, set &quot;DisplayWarning=no&quot;.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;a
    href=&quot;/download/printing/hplj_3100_3150/&quot;&gt;Reverse-engeneering
    efforts&lt;/a&gt; on the printer's protocol have already
    started, but were not finished. Anyone who makes this device
    finally working with free software please report on the the HP
    Forum here on OpenPrinting.&lt;p&gt;

    Unfortunately, this printer has a little hardware problem: The
    paper separation pad hardens with the time and the printer pulls
    in several sheets of paper at once. HP is aware of this and offers
    a kit to fix this without needing to disassemble the printer for
    free. It can be ordered for delivery into any country via their
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://h20015.www2.hp.com/en/document.jhtml?lc=en&amp;docName=bpl08107&quot;&gt;web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: cartridge&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
