<printer id="printer/HP-LaserJet_1200">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>LaserJet 1200</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser/><!--not "color"-->
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>1200</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
    <consumables>
    <!--no comments--><!--one or more "partno" elements.--></consumables>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://hpshopping.speedera.net/www.shopping.hp.com/shopping/pdf/lj1200.pdf</url>
  <lang>
    <postscript level="2">
      <ppd>PPD/HP/HP_LaserJet_1200.ppd</ppd>
    </postscript>
    <pcl level="6"/>
    <pjl/>
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <commandset>PJL,MLC,PCL,PCLXL,POSTSCRIPT</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Hewlett-Packard</manufacturer>
      <model>HP LaserJet 1200</model>
    </general>
    <usb>
      <description>Hewlett-Packard LaserJet 1200</description>
    </usb>
    <snmp>
      <description>HP LaserJet 1200</description>
    </snmp>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>pxlmono</driver>
  <!--verified-->
  <!--no "contrib_url"-->
  <comments>
    <en>
    Postscript level 2 out of the box, parallel and USB connection,
    1200n with ethernet connection, scan extension available.&lt;p&gt;

    For basic printing functionality use the Postscript PPD. For advanced functionality such
    as printer status and maintenance features, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;
    HPLIP driver&lt;/a&gt; (which includes HPIJS). &lt;p&gt;

    This printer is a good choice for a cheap laser printer (around
    400$), especially when you print a lot of text documents, as
    letters, documentation, manuals, ... for these documents it is
    really fast, as advertized by HP. But when using it on complicated
    graphics (web pages rendered by Konqueror, photo
    &quot;convert&quot;ed to PostScript with ImageMagick) in
    PostScript mode, it is very slow. If you use it in PCL mode, it is
    fast in both text and graphics printing. Therefore we recommend to
    use this printer with a GhostScript driver like
    &quot;pxlmono&quot; or &quot;hpijs&quot;.&lt;p&gt;

    Here is a somewhat longer
    review from Robert (racsw at frontiernet dot net):&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;i&gt;My testing was done on a PIII / 600Mhz machine with 256K
    of RAM installed running Mandrake Linux 8.1.  While I intended to
    use this printer as a USB connected device, I was never successful
    at getting it to work properly, and so switched over to a parallel
    port connection.  In fairness, I don&apos;t believe this is the
    fault of the printer itself. I see no
    reason why it shouldn&apos;t work on USB (&lt;/i&gt;ed: Mandrake
    8.2 configures this printer.
    automatically&lt;i&gt;).&lt;p&gt;

    IMO, the 1200/1200se is an excellent high-volume document printer,
    and those folks like myself that need to print the normal volumes
    of documents, How-To&apos;s, Installation procedures, etc, that a
    typical Linux user requires will find this printer an excellent
    choice.&lt;p&gt;

    The printer itself comes with 8Mb of memory onboard, with a 100
    pin DIMM slot capable of another 64Mb, for a total of 72Mb. In the
    testing I performed with and without this additional memory
    installed, I could find no difference in speed either way.  But
    for those who feel they want this memory anyhow, I would advise
    you purchase the Kingston module from &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.pcconnection.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.pcconnection.com/&lt;/a&gt;
    for $39.00. HP wants a whopping $470.00 (more expensive than the
    printer itself, 12x the price of the Kingston memory) for the same
    module.&lt;p&gt;

    For those wanting to print graphics on this machine, I would
    suggest an Inkjet printer instead like a DeskJet or the popular
    and proven Epson Stylus C80. If attempting to print a WYSIWYG
    rendition of a web page, I would make two suggestions.  First,
    don't use Konqueror.  Konqueror has two disadvantages.  For one,
    there is no selection for GreyScale, which, when used, cuts the
    printing time down from 10 - 15 seconds to about 2 - 3.  Secondly,
    Konqueror also does some strange things with the image, which,
    when printed, will render your copy hard to read with respect to
    font sizes and such.&lt;p&gt;
 
    Here&apos;s what OpenPrinting founder Grant Taylor
    says:&lt;p&gt;

    &quot;Konq appears to print using a Qt canvas widget feature whereby the
    canvas widget unifies the fonts - you&apos;ll see it flicker into
    small font for a moment - and generates equivalent ps code.
    Oddly, it unifies the fonts to some weird 6-point font that&apos;s
    mostly useless on paper; this is what you saw.  One can only hope
    they'll fix this in KDE3.&quot;&lt;p&gt;

    I tested most of the browsers on this printer, and by far and away
    the most readable, highest quality WYSIWYG printing was from
    Netscape.&lt;p&gt;

    But that&apos;s not what this printer is designed for. For
    documentation and online manuals, it&apos;s hard to
    beat. It&apos;s very fast, quiet and smooth.  Contrary to another
    user&apos;s report, I found the paper tray well constructed and
    easy to insert. It&apos;s strength was evidenced by finding my
    10lb (near 5 kg) house cat sitting on it one afternoon.&lt;p&gt;

    As far as the rendering speed is concerned, I think it&apos;s
    fine.  HP advertises a 10 second print time for this machine, and
    as long as you're not using Konqueror, I was able to meet this
    time consistently.  If the user selects &quot;GreyScale&quot;
    instead of color for their particular application, the time takes
    a drastic nosedive to 2-3 seconds, with the same image on the
    page as you would have seen if you had selected &quot;Color&quot;
    instead.  This 10 second time was also verified by another 1200
    user running SUSE 7.3.&lt;p&gt;

    If this printer takes longer to print, it&apos;s apparently not
    the internal rendering logic at fault, but the browser or
    application used instead.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;/i&gt;[...]&lt;i&gt; I think recommending this printer to
    others is a safe bet. It is working perfectly, and as long as I
    use it for what it&apos;s intended, it does it&apos;s job quickly
    and quietly. &lt;/i&gt;[...]&lt;i&gt; People who want to print
    graphics would probably not select a LaserJet of any variety,
    unless it&apos;s for proofing.  And then, it becomes a function of
    the application that creates and sends the job to the printer that
    determines what comes out on the page.  This I have proven after
    all these tests.&lt;p&gt;

    I would also say that I used the CUPS printing system for the
    majority of my testing, and it seems to work fine.  There was no
    bad test results that I achieved that I could attribute to the
    CUPS system itself.  Usually, with Netscape, Mozilla, Adobe
    Acrobat, etc, I would specify &quot;qtcups&quot; as the print
    command. Using &quot;lpr&quot; worked as well with no discernible
    difference.&lt;p&gt;

    I give &quot;two thumbs up&quot; for this printer for sure, and because of
    the $399 price tag, I can now justify the speed and cost-per-page
    advantage of owning a high-volume LaserJet for home
    use.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
