<printer id="printer/HP-OfficeJet_9100">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>OfficeJet 9100</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>600</x>
        <y>600</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://productfinder.support.hp.com/</url>
  <lang>
    <postscript level="2" />
    <pcl level="3" />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <ieee1284>MFG:Hewlett-Packard;MDL:officejet 9100 series;CMD:MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,BIDI-ECP;CLASS:PRINTER;</ieee1284>
      <commandset>MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,BIDI-ECP</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Hewlett-Packard</manufacturer>
      <model>officejet 9100 series</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>Postscript-HP</driver>
  <drivers>
    <driver>
      <id>Postscript-HP</id>
      <ppd>PPD/HP/hp_officejet_9100_series.ppd</ppd>
    </driver>
  </drivers>
  <comments>
    <en>

    Multifunction device: printer/scanner/copier/fax. The integrated
    flatbed scanner has an automatic document feeder and is
    legal-sized.&lt;p&gt;

    For basic printing functionality use the Postscript PPD.  For
    advanced functionality such as printer status, maintenance
    features, scanning and photo card unload use the &lt;a href=&quot;
    http://hplipopensource.com/&quot;&gt;HPLIP driver&lt;/a&gt; (which
    includes HPIJS). &lt;b&gt;NOTE:&lt;/b&gt; The PostScript PPD which
    is downloadable here is from HP, but is not included in the HPLIP
    package (HPLIP would simply use a PCL PPD). To get the best out of
    this printer use HPLIP together with the PostScript PPD from
    here.&lt;p&gt;

    Best output quality reachable with the HPLIP
    driver, especially the 1200-dpi high resolution mode gives
    excellent photo quality.&lt;p&gt;

    When used with HP's HPLIP driver, this printer
    auto-detects the paper type and does appropriate dithering and
    colour adjustment internally, controlled by the hardware. So even
    when Ghostscript with the HPLIP driver only renders
    the image with 300 or 600 dpi, the 2400x1200 dpi are used for the
    internal dithering. So if you insert photo paper, the printer will
    print in its highest quality, no paper type choice in the
    driver's options is needed. There is also a special high
    resolution mode where the image is rendered in 1200 dpi, without
    paper detection, intended for photo paper only.&lt;p&gt;

    Copying works fine from the front panel.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: HP 10 black, HP 11 color&lt;p&gt;
    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
