<printer id="printer/HP-PhotoSmart_A430">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>PhotoSmart A430</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>4800</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>www.hp.com</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3" />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>hplip</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    This is the elegant integration of a digital camera and 4x6 photo 
    printer. Designed for the easiest capture to print experience.
    It makes digital photography easier than dropping off film.
    The printer is a small (4 x 6 inch/10 x 15 cm/A6) printer 
    where the camera display becomes the printer display when the camera
    is docked on top of the printer. Video out to TV. IR remote control for
    viewing images on TV. Optional battery pack. Optional bluetooth dongle.
    New 4x8&quot; greeting card size.&lt;p&gt;

    Due to the small paper size and not using black ink its usability
    for PC documents is very limited, but it works with various PCL
    drivers which support 3-ink CMY and A6/Postcard/4x6-Photo paper
    size. Plus now a new 4x8&quot; photo greeting card size.&lt;p&gt;

    When used with HP's HPLIP driver, this printer
    auto-detects the paper type and does appropriate dithering and
    colour adjustment internally, controlled by the hardware. So even
    when Ghostscript with the HPLIP driver only renders
    the image with 300 or 600 dpi, higher resolutions are used for the
    internal dithering. So if you insert photo paper, the printer will
    print in its highest quality, no paper type choice in the
    driver's options is needed. There is also a special high
    resolution mode where the image is rendered in 1200 dpi and
    interpolated to 4800x1200 dpi by the hardware, without paper
    detection, intended for photo paper only.&lt;p&gt;

    Border-less (full bleed) printing is supported with the
    HPLIP driver.&lt;p&gt;

    To get all functionality of this printer working under Linux,
    especially also the non-printing features, like scanning, printer
    status, maintenance, and photo download from memory cards, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=hplip&quot;&gt;HPLIP
    driver package from HP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: Refill: 1 CMY color cartridge&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
