<printer id="printer/HP-PSC_2110">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>PSC 2110</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>4800</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.hp.com/cposupport/prodhome/hppsc2110x79491.html</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3" />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <ieee1284>MFG:Hewlett-Packard;MDL:PSC 2100 Series;CMD:MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,DYN;CLS:PRINTER;</ieee1284>
      <commandset>MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,DYN</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Hewlett-Packard</manufacturer>
      <model>PSC 2100 Series</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>hplip</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>
    Multi-function device: Printing, scanning, copying.&lt;p&gt;

    To get all functionality of this printer working under Linux,
    especially also the non-printing features, like scanning, printer
    status, maintenance, and photo download from memory cards, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=hplip&quot;&gt;HPLIP
    driver package from HP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

    The best printout quality you will get with the HPLIP
    driver, provided by &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://hplipopensource.com/&quot;&gt;HP&lt;/a&gt;
    (compatible to the HP DeskJet 990C), especially the 1200-dpi high
    resolution mode gives excellent photo quality (the rendered bitmap
    is 1200x1200 dpi, but the printer hardware does an interpolation
    then and prints with the printer's highest resolution). Also
    the Gimp-Print driver is reported to work (Model setting:
    &quot;pcl-900&quot;).&lt;p&gt;

    When used with HP's HPLIP driver, this printer
    auto-detects the ink cartridge type and does appropriate dithering
    and colour adjustment internally, controlled by the hardware. Note
    that in contrary to most other newer HP inkjets the paper type has
    to be adjusted on the front panel, there is no paper type
    sensor. So when Ghostscript with the HPLIP driver only
    renders the image with 300 or 600 dpi, higher resolutions are used
    for the internal dithering. There is also a special high
    resolution mode where the image is rendered in 1200 dpi and
    interpolated to 4800x1200 dpi by the hardware, intended for photo
    paper.&lt;p&gt;

    Border-less (full bleed) printing on paper sizes up to
    Oufuku-Hagaki is supported with the HPLIP
    driver.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: One Color(CMY) + one Black(K) or Photo (cmK)&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
