<printer id="printer/HP-PhotoSmart_C5100">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>PhotoSmart C5100</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>4800</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>www.hp.com</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3" />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <commandset>MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,DYN,DESKJET</commandset>
      <description>HP Photosmart C5100</description>
      <manufacturer>hp</manufacturer>
      <model>Photosmart C5100 series</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>hplip</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    It has ports on the side for inserting SmartMedia, CompactFlash,
    IBM Microdrive, SD, or Sony Memory Stick digital &quot;film&quot; and
    has a color LCD panel which displays your photos (as a digital
    camera does) so that you can select pictures to print easily. This
    way one can use the device as a digital photo lab without
    PC.&lt;p&gt;

    To get all functionality of this printer working under Linux,
    especially also the non-printing features, like scanning, printer
    status, maintenance, and photo download from memory cards, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=hplip&quot;&gt;HPLIP
    driver package from HP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

    It has a USB port on its front side to directly connect a digital
    camera (HP only).&lt;p&gt;

    Best output quality reachable with the HPLIP driver
    (printer compatible to HP DeskJet 990C), especially the 4800-dpi
    high resolution mode gives excellent photo quality.&lt;p&gt;

    When used with HP's HPLIP driver, this printer
    auto-detects the paper type and ink cartridge type and does
    appropriate dithering and colour adjustment internally, controlled
    by the hardware. So even when Ghostscript with the
    HPLIP driver only renders the image with 300 or 600
    dpi, the higher resolutions are used for the internal
    dithering. So if you insert photo paper, the printer will print in
    photo quality, no paper type choice in the driver's options
    is needed. There is also a special high resolution mode where the
    image is rendered in 1200 dpi and interpolated to 4800x1200 dpi by
    the hardware, without paper detection, intended for photo paper
    only.&lt;p&gt;

    This printer supports an optional duplex unit.&lt;p&gt;

    The key focus of the printer is to address the competitive market with regards to individual ink supplies.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: Refill: 1 black, 1 cyan, 1 magenta, 1 yellow, 1 light cyan, 1 light magenta&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
