<printer id="printer/HP-PSC_2150">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>PSC 2150</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>4800</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3" />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <ieee1284>MFG:Hewlett-Packard;MDL:PSC 2150 Series;CMD:MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,DYN;CLS:PRINTER;</ieee1284>
      <commandset>MLC,PCL,PML,DW-PCL,DYN</commandset>
      <manufacturer>Hewlett-Packard</manufacturer>
      <model>PSC 2150 Series</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>hplip</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>
    Multi-function device: Printing, scanning, copying, photo
    card access.&lt;p&gt;

    This model is available only in Japan.&lt;p&gt;

    To get all functionality of this printer working under Linux,
    especially also the non-printing features, like scanning, printer
    status, maintenance, and photo download from memory cards, use the
    &lt;a href=&quot;show_driver.cgi?driver=hplip&quot;&gt;HPLIP
    driver package from HP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

    The best printout quality you will get with the HPLIP
    driver, provided by &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://hplipopensource.com/&quot;&gt;HP&lt;/a&gt;
    (compatible to the HP DeskJet 990C), especially the 1200-dpi high
    resolution mode gives excellent photo quality (the rendered bitmap
    is 1200x1200 dpi, but the printer hardware does an interpolation
    then and prints with the printer's highest resolution). Also
    the Gimp-Print driver is reported to work (Model setting:
    &quot;pcl-900&quot;).&lt;p&gt;

    When used with HP's HPLIP driver, this printer
    auto-detects the paper type and ink cartridge type and does
    appropriate dithering and colour adjustment internally, controlled
    by the hardware. So when Ghostscript with the HPLIP
    driver only renders the image with 300 or 600 dpi, higher
    resolutions are used for the internal dithering. So if you insert
    photo paper, the printer will print in photo quality, no paper
    type choice in the driver's options is needed. There is also
    a special high resolution mode where the image is rendered in 1200
    dpi and interpolated to 4800x1200 dpi by the hardware, without
    paper detection, intended for photo paper only.&lt;p&gt;

    Border-less (full bleed) printing on paper sizes up to
    Oufuku-Hagaki is supported with the HPLIP
    driver.&lt;p&gt;

    In addition this device copies and prints photos directly
    from CompactFlash, SmartMedia, and Memory Stick, but these
    functions are currently only controllable by the front panel, not
    by the PC. To choose photos from your memory card, the machine
    makes an index sheet with thumbnails of all photos and you can
    mark which photos you want to print and how they should get
    printed with a pen on the sheet and then you scan the sheet to
    execute the printing job.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: One Color(CMY) + one Black(K) or Photo (cmK)&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
