<printer id="printer/HP-PhotoSmart_P100">
  <make>HP</make>
  <model>PhotoSmart P100</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet/>
    <color/>
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>2400</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
    <consumables>
      <comments>
        <en>Refill: 1 CMY color cartridge</en>
      </comments>
    <!--one or more "partno" elements.--></consumables>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.hp.com/cposupport/prodhome/hpphotosma43045.html</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3"/><!--no pjl-->
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <ieee1284>MFG:HP;MDL:PHOTOSMART 100;CMD:MLC,PCL,PML,BIDI-ECP,ECP18,DW-PCL;CLS:PRINTER;DES:hp photosmart 100;</ieee1284>
      <manufacturer>HP</manufacturer>
      <model>PHOTOSMART 100</model>
      <description>hp photosmart 100</description>
      <commandset>MLC,PCL,PML,BIDI-ECP,ECP18,DW-PCL</commandset>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>hpijs</driver>
  <!--verified--><!--no "contrib_url"-->
  <comments>
    <en>
    This is a small (4 x 6 inch/10 x 15 cm/A6) printer especially for
    printing photos taken with digital cameras. It has ports on the
    side for inserting SmartMedia, CompactFlash, and Memory Stick
    digital &quot;film&quot; and has an LCD panel that lets you select
    pictures from the &quot;film&quot; to print, so one can use the
    device as a digital photo lab without PC.&lt;p&gt;

    Due to the small paper size and not using black ink its usability
    for PC documents is very limited, but it works with various PCL
    drivers which support 3-ink CMY and A6/Postcard/4x6-Photo paper
    size. If the driver does not support such small paper formats the
    upper left corner of the page is printed. The best quality you
    will get with &quot;hpijs&quot; which supports this printer
    explicitly since version 1.0&lt;p&gt;

    For basic printing functionality use the &lt;a href=&quot;
    http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;HPIJS driver &lt;/a&gt;. 
    For advanced functionality such as printer status, maintenance 
    features, and photo card unload use the &lt;a href=&quot;
    http://hplip.sf.net/&quot;&gt;HPLIP driver&lt;/a&gt; 
    (which includes HPIJS). &lt;p&gt;

    When used with HP&apos;s &quot;hpijs&quot; driver, this printer
    auto-detects the paper type and does appropriate dithering and
    colour adjustment internally, controlled by the hardware. So even
    when GhostScript with the &quot;hpijs&quot; driver only renders
    the image with 300 or 600 dpi, the higher resolutions are used for
    the internal dithering. So if you insert photo paper, the printer
    will print in its highest quality, no paper type choice in the
    driver&apos;s options is needed. There is also a special high
    resolution mode where the image is rendered in 1200 dpi, without
    paper detection, intended for photo paper only.&lt;p&gt;

    Border-less (full bleed) printing is supported with the
    &quot;hpijs&quot; driver.&lt;p&gt;
    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>

