<printer id="printer/Lexmark-Z13">
  <make>Lexmark</make>
  <model>Z13</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>2400</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.lexmark.com/printers/inkjet/Z13/index.html</url>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
  </lang>
  <functionality>F</functionality>
  <comments>
    <en>

    Ultra-cheap (40$) inkjet printer, allows only to use one cartridge
    at a time, either 3-color (32$) or black (29$). Coming with only a
    colour cartridge and Lexmark cartridges being known to be
    expensive this printer is a very expensive solution in terms of
    the per-page cost. In addition probably the mechanics is very
    flimsy. I (Till) have the Z22 in my test rack and this model is
    already bad enough, and in addition, a simple calculation tells
    you that they sell you the mechanics for only 8 bucks, assuming
    that the cartridge coming with the printer is not a half-full
    starter cartridge. So one can even not recommend this printer to
    Windows users.&lt;p&gt;

    Unfortunately, there is no free software driver, but &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.lexmark.com&quot;&gt;Lexmark&lt;/a&gt;
    provides a Linux/x86 binary-only driver. To get it, simply follow
    the &quot;Drivers&quot; link on the home page. The drivers issued
    by Lexmark do not contain any CUPS or PDQ configuration file, so
    use them either with LPD or with my &lt;a
    href=&quot;download/printing/lexmark-foomatic-kit.tar.gz&quot;&gt;Lexmark
    Foomatic Kit&lt;/a&gt;. Download it, uncompress it, and follow the
    instructions of its README file. Due to having access to all
    options of the driver it leads even to a better printout quality
    than the Lexmark driver with its original configuration
    software.&lt;p&gt;

    There are unsubstantiated rumours that this printer does now work
    with one of the free Lexmark drivers.  If so do tell!&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: color or black ink cartridge&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
