<printer id="printer/Lexmark-Z32">
  <make>Lexmark</make>
  <model>Z32</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>1200</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.lexmark.com/US/Products/printers/0,2792,MTEyfDE=,00.html</url>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <commandset>LNPAP</commandset>
      <description>Lexmark Z22-Z32</description>
      <manufacturer>Lexmark</manufacturer>
      <model>Lexmark Z22-Z32</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>D</functionality>
  <driver>lxm3200-tweaked</driver>
  <contrib_url>http://drivers.lexmark.com/drivers.nsf/printer+driver/D24884EA9A4F28EA8525698A004C48AA?OpenDocument</contrib_url>
  <comments>
    <en>

    Prints with the lxm3200 driver in all resolutions, but only in
    bidirectional mode, colours off (I think it is a Ghostscript
    problem), 300 dpi too light, 600 too dark, 1200 flooded with
    ink.&lt;p&gt;

    This printer is really slow and somewhat flimsy. It is capable of
    fairly good output, though.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lexmark.com&quot;&gt;Lexmark&lt;/a&gt;
    provides a Linux/x86 binary-only driver for this printer.  &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.picante.com/~gtaylor/&quot;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt;
    have this printer and a beta of the driver; the combo works fairly
    well. But don't buy the thing because of this; buy a printer
    that works with proper free software.&lt;p&gt;

    To obtain the driver simply follow the &quot;Drivers&quot; link on
    the home page. Lexmark's driver does not work with Debian
    Woody using alien, and it indeed isn't listed as
    supported.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;
    galaxie:~# lexmarkz32
    lexmarkz32: Symbol `__ti7VDKForm' has different size in shared object, consider re-linking
    lexmarkz32: error while loading shared libraries: lexmarkz32: undefined symbol: __7VDKFormP14VDKApplicationPci13GtkWindowType
    &lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;

    ...bummer. It works against Debian potato and Helix Gnome; that
    library error probably stems from a mismatch between the expected
    Gtk library (the gui is built using vdk, a c++ wrapper thing, I
    guess) and whatever you've got. I would expect the z32 binary
    to still work. Then you can print with all spoolers using the
    Lexmark Foomatic Kit mentioned below.&lt;p&gt;

    The drivers issued by Lexmark do not contain any CUPS or PDQ
    configuration file, so use them either with LPD or with my &lt;a
    href=&quot;download/printing/lexmark-foomatic-kit.tar.gz&quot;&gt;Lexmark
    Foomatic Kit&lt;/a&gt;. Download it, uncompress it, and follow the
    instructions of its README file. Due to having access to all
    options of the driver it leads even to a better printout quality
    than the Lexmark driver with its original configuration
    software.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: Color, Black (or Photo instead of Black) Separate. $28.91@inkfar&lt;p&gt;</en>
  </comments>
</printer>
