<printer id="printer/Lexmark-Z22">
  <make>Lexmark</make>
  <model>Z22</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>1200</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
  </lang>
  <autodetect>
    <general>
      <commandset>LNPAP</commandset>
      <description>Lexmark Z22-Z32</description>
      <manufacturer>Lexmark</manufacturer>
      <model>Lexmark Z22-Z32</model>
    </general>
  </autodetect>
  <functionality>D</functionality>
  <driver>lxm3200-tweaked</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    This is exactly the same printer as the Z32, but it is delivered
    with only the colour cartridge, so that the user does expensive
    CMY printing when he does not buy a black cartridge. The manual
    and the Windows drivers CD is the same for both printers.&lt;p&gt;

    Prints with the lxm3200 driver in all resolutions, but only in
    bidirectional mode, colours off (I think it is a Ghostscript
    problem), 300 dpi too light, 600 too dark, 1200 flooded with
    ink.&lt;p&gt;

    The Z22 works excellently with the proprietary driver which &lt;a
    href=&quot;http://www.lexmark.com&quot;&gt;Lexmark&lt;/a&gt; has
    published for the &lt;a
    href=&quot;show_printer.cgi?recnum=Lexmark-Z32&quot;&gt;Z32&lt;/a&gt;. See
    also this posting on our Lexmark forum:&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;
    Subject: Lexmark Z22 &amp;amp; linux
    Date: 18 Dec 2000 06:32:04 GMT
    From: coderman@mindspring.com (coder)
    
    I have been able to successfully print on the Z22 using the drivers
    provided by lexmark for the Z32.  You can find them on their website (i
    think www.lexmrk.com)
    &lt;/pre&gt;

    The drivers issued by Lexmark do not contain any CUPS or PDQ
    configuration file, so use them either with LPD or with my &lt;a
    href=&quot;download/printing/lexmark-foomatic-kit.tar.gz&quot;&gt;Lexmark
    Foomatic Kit&lt;/a&gt;. Download it, uncompress it, and follow the
    instructions of its README file. Due to having access to all
    options of the driver it leads even to a better printout quality
    than the Lexmark driver with its original configuration
    software.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: color + black or color + photo ink cartridge&lt;p&gt;

</en>
  </comments>
</printer>
