<printer id="printer/NEC-PinWriter_P6_plus">
  <make>NEC</make>
  <model>PinWriter P6 plus</model>
  <mechanism>
    <dotmatrix />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>360</x>
        <y>360</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
    <text>
      <charset>us-ascii</charset>
    </text>
  </lang>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>necp6</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>Color is an optional feature for this printer.&lt;p&gt;
Some info contributed by Sebastian Leske (Sebastian dot Leske at bigfoot dot de):&lt;p&gt;
The information about the NEC P6+ in the database is basically correct. I
own one and I can confirm that it works fine with Ghostscript's necp6
driver. 
&lt;p&gt;
There are three things I'd like to add, though:
&lt;p&gt;
1) 
The necp6 driver does not seem to support colour printing (at least I
could not figure out how).
&lt;p&gt;
As noted in the database, color is only available via an accessory that
must be bought separately. If you have it and want to print in color, you
can use one of the Epson drivers in Ghostscript (don't remember which, but
I tried it, think it was 'epsonc'). The NEC P6+ can emulate Epson color
printers, so this works.
&lt;p&gt;
The quality is not quite as good as with a native color driver under
Win95, but for colored text / linedrawings it's ok. You would not want to
print photos with the NEC P6+ anyway, the results are very weak compared
to modern injet printers.
&lt;p&gt;
2) 
The printer cannot print on the top 20 mm or so of the page. Ghostscript
does not seem to know about this, so everything you print will be shifted
downward on the page by about 20 mm. This should be kept in mind when
laying out a page for printing.
&lt;p&gt;
Actually, normally the unprintable area at the top is even longer, but you
can configure the printer to minimize the unprintable area by not putting
down the paper guide wheel until after printing the first line. See
handbook for details.
&lt;p&gt;
3)
Using address labels via the tractor feed works fine under Linux, you just
need to send the printer precision line feeds between the text for each
label to advance to the next label. The codes are in the handbook, or
email me for details. I made a perl script which outputs the appropriate
control codes.
&lt;p&gt;
Note: Don't print address labels in graphics mode (i.e. via ghostscript),
send the printer text, so it uses its internal fonts. Text printed in
graphics mode often comes out bad, because the linefeeds with tractor-fed
labels are somewhat irregular. In graphics mode, a linefeed may occur in
the middle of a line, then the bottom half and the top half of a line of
text may be separated or run into each other.
&lt;p&gt;
</en>
  </comments>
</printer>
