<printer id="printer/Samsung-CLP-510">
  <make>Samsung</make>
  <model>CLP-510</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>1200</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.samsung.com/Products/PrinterandMultifunction/ColorLaserPrinters/CLP_510NXAA.asp</url>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
  </lang>
  <functionality>D</functionality>
  <driver>splix</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    This is a cheap color laser printer with a proprietary
    language. Samsung provides a closed-source driver on their web
    site, the &quot;Unified Linux Driver&quot;, a driver package containing CUPS
    drivers and PPDs for all Samsung printers. Version 2.00.90 and
    newer supports also this printer. Output is raster-only, and due
    to glitches in the software, monochrome sources are output as
    color (visible flecks of cyan, magenta, and yellow). It is also
    not easy to install this driver in arbitrary distributions. See
    the user reports below.&lt;p&gt;

    As the first free software printer driver SpliX supports this
    printer, but the driver still needs testing. So please try out
    this printer with SpliX and report your results to the author of
    the driver.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;hr&gt;

    User reports:&lt;p&gt;

    I have installed and de-installed the printer a few times using
    the driver from Samsung (2.0.90).  I am using Ubuntu 6.06.  I have
    managed to get it to print a test page in KDE and Cups, but it
    only prints half the page and the bottom is blank.  Before that,
    it printed a test page that was full of errors about
    PCL.&lt;p&gt;

    The printer does work with Cups Version &amp;lt; 2 and the
    provided proprietary drivers. It will print out white pages unless
    you specify the locale to eg. POSIX (eg. &quot;LC_ALL=POSIX lpr
    test.ps&quot;).&lt;p&gt;

    The proprietary driver does just support 600dpi.&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;hr&gt;

    I use Suse 10.1 and I installed the Samsung unified driver
    2.00.90.  The printer works BUT:

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;no choice for resolution;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;duplex doesn't work.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;hr&gt;

    Overall, it's a cheap color laser printer and a pretty good
    value, but the lack of support for other operating systems makes
    it a little less than attractive.  Print quality is decent while
    lacking options that are supported by the Windows driver, and be
    prepared for the printer to put up a fight as you try to use it.
    The driver seems to crash when printing certain things (mostly
    webpages), and there is no support from Samsung for the driver and
    no specification of the SPL-C language available.  While I
    haven't determined the exact reason of the crash, it seems to
    be due to the custom backend filters the Samsung driver uses.  It
    very well could be a combination of a broken build of my system
    (an older build of Gentoo) and using an Athlon64, but the issue
    seems very similar to the first user's comments.  The output
    will stop randomly in the middle of a page, and syslog will show a
    segfault in gs, though recompiling ghostscript doesn't seem
    to change the issue.&lt;p&gt;

    I wasn't able to reproduce the &quot;prints black with
    expensive color toner&quot; bug mentioned above.  I examined the
    CUPS test page, printed with the proprietary Linux drivers, and
    with Acrobat under Windows.  Neither showed flecks of color in or
    around black areas, but the linux version was clearly 600 dpi,
    while the windows version was at 1200.  Color matching under linux
    is wrong; the &quot;blue&quot; pie wedge comes out purple.  The
    drivers ship with *.cms files that look like color profiles, but I
    don't know how to install them yet.&lt;p&gt;

    Duplex can be set via the printer's front panel and LCD
    display; the setting via cups doesn't work (although enabling
    duplex via cups adds a blank page to the end of each odd-length
    document...). I'm using version 2.00.90 of the drivers, and
    have seen no stability problems in the ~10 pages I've printed
    under linux so far.&lt;p&gt;

    Be warned that the samsung driver installer attempts to install
    older versions of standard c++ libraries into /usr/ without
    prompting.  According to its documentation, it also replaces lpr
    with a &quot;GUI LPR&quot; that will pop up a dialog when you
    print.  If you download the samsung drivers, you may prefer to
    manually install them.  The drivers include binaries for i386 and
    x86_64.  Put the stuff from the appropriate &quot;filter&quot; and
    &quot;ppd&quot; directories into /usr/lib/cups/filter/ and
    /usr/share/ppd/Samsung, respectively.  (The directories should
    already exist, and may vary between linux distributions.) Then,
    install the printer via the CUPS web gui (&lt;a
    href=&quot;http://localhost:631/).&quot;&gt;http://localhost:631/).&lt;/a&gt;
    The drivers shoud show up under &quot;SAMSUNG&quot;.  Apparently,
    you used to need to create a file called /etc/linuxprint.cfg.  I
    didn't have to do that.&lt;p&gt;

    Install Samsung CLP-510 color laser printer to Ubunutu dapper
    i386 &amp;amp; x86_64&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;tt&gt;sudo adduser cupsys shadow&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    Insert in /etc/udev/rules.d/60-symlinks.rules&lt;br&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;# Create symlink for usb printer to /dev/usb/lp*&lt;br&gt;
    BUS==&quot;usb&quot;,
    KERNEL==&quot;lp[0-9]*&quot;,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
    SYMLINK+=&quot;usb/%k&quot;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    restart udev:&lt;br&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;/etc/init.d/udev restart&lt;br&gt;
    /etc/init.d/cupsys restart&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    download latest Samsung CLP-510 driver from
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://downloadcenter.samsung.com/content/DR/200607/20060719124812000_UnifiedLinuxDriver.tar.gz&quot;&gt;http://downloadcenter.samsung.com/content/DR/200607/20060719124812000_UnifiedLinuxDriver.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;tar -zxvf 20060719124812000_UnifiedLinuxDriver.tar.gz&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    The package will create a folder called cdroot&lt;br&gt; The package
    offers an automatic setup, but it doen't work for me, I can
    only print half page, therefore, I uninstalled and create it
    manually.&lt;br&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;cd cdroot/Linux&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    You'll find 3 folders, i386;noarch&amp;amp;x86_64&lt;br&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;/cdroot/Linux$ cp noarch/at_root/etc/sane.d/smfp.conf /etc/sane.d/&lt;br&gt;
    /cdroot/Linux$ cp noarch/at_opt/share/ppd/CLP-510splc.ppd
    /usr/share/ppd/linuxprinting.org-gs-builtin/&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    now we have to go either i386 or x86_64 depends on your distro&lt;br&gt;
    For x86_64 we choose x86_64 folder&lt;br&gt;

    &lt;tt&gt;/cdroot/Linux$ cp x86_64/at_root/usr/lib64/libmfp.so.1.0.1 /usr/lib64/&lt;br&gt;
    /cdroot/Linux$ cp x86_64/at_root/usr/lib64/cups/backend/mfp
    /usr/lib64/cups/backend/&lt;br&gt;
    /cdroot/Linux$ cp x86_64/at_root/usr/lib64/cups/filter/*
    /usr/lib64/cups/filter/&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;

    now use CUPS' web interface or your distribution's
    printer setup tool to add the printer&lt;br&gt; when prompt for
    userid and passwd use root and root password&lt;br&gt; hope this
    help&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;hr&gt;

    rpc(at)belug.org adds:&lt;p&gt;

    My distribution is Debian Etch and my installation with the above
    mentioned &quot;Unified Driver&quot; worked. It installs below
    /opt within Cups you make the definitive switch! You choose
    &lt;tt&gt;/opt/Samsung/mfp/share/ppd/CLP-510spld.ppd&lt;/tt&gt; as
    your favorite PPD - file because the CLP-510 is not listed in the
    list of Samsung printers. The PPD - file of version 1.9 (shipped
    with my printer in 02/2006) is errornous and therefore not
    useable. Then you have to change the paperformat from Letter to A4
    ( ;-) ) and switch on duplex within CUPS and then the printer
    works perfectly. CUPS says it has 600dpi, but whether it has 600
    or 1200dpi I won't mind: I am too old to see the
    difference.&lt;p&gt;

    HTH&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: B, C, M, Y, total UKP 240&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
