<printer id="printer/Samsung-ML-2570">
  <make>Samsung</make>
  <model>ML-2570</model>
  <url>http://samsung.com/Products/PrinterandMultifunction/BlackWhiteLaserforHomeHomeOffice/ML_2571NXAA.asp</url>
  <lang>
    <postscript level="3" />
    <pcl level="6" />
  </lang>
  <functionality>B</functionality>
  <driver>hpijs-pcl5e</driver>
  <drivers>
    <driver>
      <id>Postscript</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>pxlmono</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>lj5gray</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>hpijs-pcl5e</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>ljet4</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>lj4dith</id>
    </driver>
    <driver>
      <id>gdi</id>
    </driver>
  </drivers>
  <comments>
    <en> 

      It seems that at least some copies of this printer have a firmware 
      bug which results in problems with the PostScript and PCL-XL modes.
      In these modes the first job after turning on the printer is printer
      correctly but subsequent jobs come out as garbage characters in text
      mode, as if the printer did not get the beginning of the file and
      then prints the rest as text. Turning off the printer and turning it
      on again allows one correct PostScript or PCL-XL job again. The
      printer works reliably in PCL-5e mode though. Therefore the
      "hpijs-pcl5e" driver is the recommended driver. So if your printer
      has the described problem, switch to the hpijs-pcl5e driver and
      turn it off and on again. See &lt;a
      href=&quot;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/foomatic-db/+bug/855412&quot;&gt;this
      Ubuntu bug report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

      Bug in Samsung-supplied PPD-file: OpenOffice.org 2.0 seems to
      have a problem with the ML-2570ps-ppd driver - it only prints in
      the top right-hand quarter of the page. OOo works fine with the
      generic PCL6 driver (pxlmono) and Postscript driver. No other
      applications known to have any problems with the ML-2570ps.ppd
      driver. This can be fixed by editing the ML-2570ps.ppd-file, which
      has a bug. Simply delete or edit the first line after
      &quot;*DefaultPaperDimension: A4&quot;. It is saying something
      like *PaperDimension A4/A4: &quot;842 1191&quot;, which is
      defining the paper size of A3. The correct entries for A4 are some
      lines below. So either delete this line or replace it by
      *PaperDimension A3/A3: &quot;842 1191&quot;&lt;p&gt;
      
      Foomatic entry made by PPDtoXML T/G 0.20 on 2008-09-07

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
