<printer id="printer/Samsung-ML-1410">
  <make>Samsung</make>
  <model>ML-1410</model>
  <mechanism>
    <laser />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>600</x>
        <y>600</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <lang>
    <proprietary />
  </lang>
  <functionality>A</functionality>
  <driver>gdi</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>

    Very cheap (around 140 EUR) and compact laser printer with fully
    integrated horizontal paper tray.&lt;p&gt;

    The ML-1410 and the ML-1510 seem to have the same electronics
    inside, as both identify themselves as ML-1510. So don't
    worry when your distribution automatically &quot;upgrades&quot; your ML-1410
    to an ML-1510.&lt;p&gt;

    Currently Samsung supports this printer with proprietary drivers which
    come with the printer on its driver CD or can be downloaded on the web
    sites of Samsung. Unfortunately, these drivers do not work necessarily
    with all Linux distributions.&lt;p&gt;

    As nearly all of Samsung's low-cost lasers use the same
    proprietary printer language (during the time it eas called
    SmartGDI, PrinThru, and SPL) on can also use a free Ghostscript
    driver which Samsung published some time ago for the
    ML-4500.&lt;p&gt;

    They provided a Ghostscript RPM and an installer that adjusts Red
    Hat's printtool or printconf-gui. There was also a PPD for
    distros using CUPS (as Mandrake 7.2 or newer) and a possibility to
    integrate the driver in SuSE's APS filters. For users of
    other distributions/printing systems (especially the current
    CUPS/Foomatic environments) appropriate Foomatic information is
    provided here in the &quot;gdi&quot; driver entry.&lt;p&gt;

    Stupidly, Samsung has named the driver &quot;gdi&quot;. This name
    is confusing, because the driver supports only Samsungs GDI
    printers. SuSE has called it &quot;samsunggdi&quot;, in ESP Ghostscript both
    names can be used.&lt;p&gt;

    The driver was removed from Samsung's website but a copy with
    some improvements is available &lt;a
    href=&quot;/download/printing/samsung-gdi/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Also
    ESP Ghostscript contains this driver.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: Toner and drum in one unit, around 80 EUR&lt;p&gt;

    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
