<printer id="printer/Sharp-AJ-2000">
  <make>Sharp</make>
  <model>AJ-2000</model>
  <mechanism>
    <inkjet />
    <color />
    <resolution>
      <dpi>
        <x>1200</x>
        <y>1200</y>
      </dpi>
    </resolution>
  </mechanism>
  <url>http://www.sharpelectronics.com/</url>
  <lang>
    <pcl level="3?" />
  </lang>
  <functionality>B</functionality>
  <driver>pcl3</driver>
  <comments>
    <en>
    Same printer as the Xerox DocuPrint M760, the printer does up to
    1200 dpi, but the drivers shown here do only 600. The printer is
    rather fast in 600 dpi, so it serves well for black text simple
    graphics, web pages, ...&lt;p&gt;

    One can even print photos, but not in such a high quality as you
    get from HP or Epson inkjets. To do so, one has to use the
    &quot;pcl3&quot; driver (version 3.3 or newer, printer needs to be
    initialized for every page with the new
    &quot;-dConfigureEveryPage&quot; option), the
    &quot;sharp.upp&quot; prints all colours which contain black ink
    totally in gray, so the result looks like a black-and-white image
    with some parts shown in colour. The same you get with the default
    settings of &quot;pcl3&quot;, you must choose &quot;CMY+K&quot;
    for the &quot;ColorMode&quot; setting (probably one cannot mix the
    black ink and the colour inks of this printer and the printer
    refuses mixing the inks internally). In addition, you should set
    up 600 dpi, Floyd-Steinberg dithering, &quot;Presentation&quot;
    quality, and a Gamma correction of around 3 (otherwise the image
    gets way too dark). There is no option for a gamma correction in
    &quot;pcl3&quot;, but if you use CUPS as the spooler you can use the
    &quot;gamma&quot; option of CUPS (&quot;&lt;tt&gt;lpoptions -P
    &amp;lt;printer&amp;gt; -o
    gamma=3000&lt;/tt&gt;&quot;). Ghostscript and GIMP have also
    possibilities for a Gamma correction. The colour quality gets much
    better when using coated inkjet paper (media type setting
    &quot;Bond Paper&quot;) or photo paper (media type setting
    &quot;Glossy Paper&quot;). Printing in &quot;CMY&quot; mode or
    with more than 2 &quot;Black Levels&quot; or &quot;CMY
    Levels&quot; does not work.&lt;p&gt;

    The Sharp AJ-1800/1805/2000/2005 and the Xerox DocuPrint M750/M760
    are very similar and can all be used with the same drivers. My
    experience with the Sharp AJ-2000 described here is probably also
    applicable to the other models.&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

      Consumables/Refills: Seperately exchangable tanks for each colour&lt;p&gt;
    </en>
  </comments>
</printer>
